[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫·马兰：好的
Welcome to Introduction to Game Development.
欢迎来到游戏开发入门
My name is David Malan, and this is Colton Ogden.
我叫大卫·马兰 这位是科尔顿·奥格登
And this is a class that assumes only a class like CS50,
这是一个只假设CS50这样的类的类
which is the colleges and the extension schools introduction to computer
哪一所大学和推广学校是计算机导论
science but more generally we just assume
科学 但更普遍的是 我们只是假设
that you have prior programming experience in most any language
你以前有过几乎所有语言的编程经验
and therefore have some comfort with some
因此对一些人有一些安慰
of the basic constructs of programming.
编程的基本结构
But we assume no background in Lua or Lab 2D or any of the frameworks
但我们假设没有Lua或Lab 2D或任何框架的背景
that we'll be using in the class.
我们会在课堂上用到
All of that lies ahead.
所有这一切都在前面
So, if you're like me, you probably grew up with video games of some sort.
所以 如果你和我一样 你可能是伴随着某种电子游戏长大的
And when you maybe started programming, the programming environments
当你开始编程时 编程环境
were perhaps very text based, black and white terminal window, and the like.
可能非常基于文本、黑白终端窗口等
And maybe you did something graphical with a language like scratch or Alice
也许你用Scratch或Alice之类的语言做了一些图形化的事情
or beyond, or if you're in the world of the web,
或者更远的地方 或者如果你身处网络世界
you've made more graphical applications of some sort, but still pretty static.
您已经制作了更多的图形化应用程序 但仍然非常静态
The sort of content comes on the screen, then the content changes, and so forth.
内容的种类出现在屏幕上 然后内容发生变化 以此类推
And it's a little less obvious if you're a little newer to programming
如果你是编程新手 这就不那么明显了
how you go about creating some of those games
你是如何去创造一些这样的游戏的
from yesteryear with which you all grew up,
从你们一起长大的昨天开始
where there's a lot more animation, there's a lot more asynchronicity,
哪里有更多的动画 哪里就有更多的异步性
lots of things happening at the same time.
很多事情同时发生
A lot of events happening, and you all NOT--
发生了很多事情 而你们都没有--
not only want to capture this interactivity,
不仅想要捕捉这种互动性
but also want to respond to events that are
但也想要对那些
happening, especially if you have players
发生了 特别是如果你有球员的话
elsewhere next to you or online.
在你旁边的其他地方或在线上
And so the way the course will be structured
因此 课程的结构将是
is through a narrative of these various games, many of which
是通过对这些不同的游戏的叙述 其中许多
you might have played yourself.
你可能扮演了你自己
But over the course of the semester, we dive
但在这学期的课程中 我们潜水
into the context of each of these games and look
深入到每一场比赛的背景下 看看
at some of the underlying principles, the constructs via which
在一些基本的原则 通过这些结构
they were built up, and really use them as a point of departure
它们是建立起来的 并真正地把它们作为出发点
for talking about those various capabilities
谈论这些不同的能力
that you might integrate into your own games.
你可以把它融入到你自己的游戏中
And then punctuating the semester, ultimately,
最后 在整个学期
will be a number of milestones.
将是一系列里程碑
Some in the form of smaller assignments that are meant to reinforce just some
有些是以小作业的形式
of the more recent material and sort of set you up for success when the course
最近的材料 并为你的成功做好准备
is deeper and more hands on projects. , Because indeed,
是更深入和更多地参与项目 因为
the project is where you'll build or extend some of your own games.
该项目是你将建立或扩展一些自己的游戏
And then the class itself will culminate at the very end of the semester
然后这门课本身会在学期末达到高潮
with your very own final project, an opportunity to propose,
你们自己的期末项目 一个求婚的机会
to design, and implement a game that somehow or other draws
设计并实现一个游戏
upon the course's lessons.
课程的教训
So that when you walk out of here in just a few months' time,
所以当你几个月后离开这里的时候
you've not only played your fair share of games,
你不仅玩了很多游戏
but have actually built several of your own.
但实际上你自己也造了几个
So without further ado, allow me to turn things
废话少说 请允许我把事情
over to Colton for a look and a stroll through yesteryear's Pong.
去科尔顿看一看 在去年的乒乓球上漫步
COLTON OGDEN: Thanks, David.
科尔顿·奥格登：谢谢 大卫
I'm very excited to begin teaching you guys this course
我很高兴能开始教你们这门课
because game development was actually what got me
因为游戏开发让我
into programming in the first place.
编程的人
I remember back in 2006 or 2007 buying this book here,
我记得2006年或2007年在这里买了这本书
3D Game Programming All In One, which was a look through 3D game programming.
3D Game Programming All In One 这是一个3D游戏编程的外观
And it was a monolithic text in the context of a game engine
这是一个游戏引擎中的整体文本
that was popular in the late 2000s called Torque.
在2000年代后期很流行的一种叫做扭矩的技术
It's not as in vogue these days, but it at the time was pretty popular,
现在不流行了 但在当时很流行
and it used a language called TorqueScript.
and it used运用a language语言called叫TorqueScript扭矩.
And I remember reading through this book and seeing all this code,
我记得我读过这本书 看到了所有的代码
and I had never seen like source code at all before,
and I had never seen看到like source源code码at all before
or had ever been introduced to programming.
或者曾经接触过编程
And, frankly, I found it quite intimidating,
坦白说 我觉得这很吓人
because I was looking at all the syntax that I didn't understand,
因为我看了所有我不懂的语法
and I didn't know anything about game development.
我对游戏开发一无所知
I had always played games growing up and been fascinated by it,
我从小到大一直在玩游戏 并被它迷住了
but as I started getting more comfortable with computers
但当我开始更习惯使用电脑时
and I started to get more curious about it
我开始对它产生了更多的好奇
and realized that it was a major profession,
并意识到这是一个主要的职业
I started to dive a little deeper.
我开始往下潜得更深一些
This was my first foray.
这是我的第一次尝试
And after spending a little bit of time away from it
在花了一点时间离开它之后
after looking through the source code for a TorqueScript, which
在查看了TorqueScrip的源代码后 它
was rather arcane, a lot of percent symbols and dollar signs
相当神秘 有很多百分号和美元符号
are the weird things that I just hadn't gotten my mind around.
都是我还没想清楚的奇怪的事情
I went back to it, started to really learn the basics of programming
我又回到了那里 开始真正学习编程的基础知识
and other languages, like Python and c and c++,
以及其他语言 如Python、c和c++
and I grew to really like programming and computer science a lot.
我逐渐变得非常喜欢编程和计算机科学
And here's just an image of what Torque looked like at the time.
这只是一张当时扭矩的图像
It was really the sort of predecessor to Unity nowadays.
这真的是Unity现在的前身
Although, in my opinion, Unity does things a lot better.
虽然 在我看来 统一做事情要好得多
It was more accessible, it uses languages that are more in vogue
它更容易使用 它使用的语言更时髦
and popular and used by other people already in other domains.
并且已经在其他领域的其他人流行和使用
And so we'll be covering Unity at the tail end of the course.
因此 我们将在课程的末尾介绍“团结”
So we'll be covering predominantly 2D game development.
因此 我们将主要介绍2D游戏开发
But the topics that we'll be covering today
但我们今天要讲的话题
as we get started in the context of Pong are these bullet points here.
我们在Pong的背景下开始的时候 这里有一些要点
Lua, which will be the language that we're using predominately
Lua 这将是我们主要使用的语言
throughout the course, which is a dynamic scripting language very
在整个课程中 这是一种非常动态的脚本语言
similar to Python and JavaScript.
类似于Python和Java脚本
We'll be covering LOVE 2D as our primary game framework, which
我们将把Love 2D作为我们的主要游戏框架 它
is a runtime and a framework which exposes all of its methods
是一个运行库和一个公开其所有方法的框架
for drawing, audio, input, etc.
用于绘图、音频、输入等
via Lua, so that it's very easy to write code very quickly,
通过Lua 所以很容易非常快速地编写代码
but get very good results.
但取得了非常好的效果
And the documentation for their framework is superb, in my opinion.
在我看来 他们框架的文档是一流的
Today we'll be talking about a few just basic principles
今天我们将讨论几个基本原则
as we get our feet wet with game development.
当我们涉足游戏开发的时候
Things like drawing shapes, drawing text,
比如绘制形状、绘制文本、
these are both very big aspects of Pong, which
这两个都是乒乓球非常大的方面
is just a very simple game based on shapes and text
是一个基于形状和文本的非常简单的游戏
moving around the screen.
在屏幕上移动
We'll be talking about Delta Time and Velocity, which Delta Time is probably
我们将讨论增量时间和速度 这可能是增量时间
arguably one of the most important variables
可以说 最重要的变量之一
that we keep track of in any game framework or engine, which is just
我们在任何游戏框架或引擎中都会跟踪 这只是
the amount of time that's elapsed since the last frame of execution
自最后一帧执行以来经过的时间量
in our game, measured in LOVE 2D in terms of seconds, fractions of seconds.
在我们的游戏中 以2D爱情来衡量 以秒为单位 几分之一秒
We'll be talking about game state, because you
我们将谈论游戏状态 因为你
can have a state in your game.
在你的游戏中可以有一个状态
You can be at the title screen, you can be playing, you can be in a menu.
你可以在标题屏幕上 你可以在玩 你可以在菜单中
This will, obviously, be very important because you want different update logic
显然 这将非常重要 因为您需要不同的更新逻辑
and rendering logic depending on what state you're in.
以及根据您所处的状态呈现逻辑
We'll be talking about basic object oriented programming,
我们将讨论基本的面向对象编程
for those who might be unfamiliar coming from C.
对于那些可能不熟悉来自C
It's basically a way of encapsulating our data, any of our game objects,
它基本上是一种封装我们的数据、任何游戏对象的方式
in such a way that the variables that are relevant to them
以这样一种方式 与它们相关的变量
are put together, along with functions that will operate on that data.
与将对该数据进行操作的函数放在一起
So instead of having like 20 different variables for all
所以不是所有变量都有20个不同的变量
these different objects that you have to keep track of in your code,
您必须在代码中跟踪这些不同的对象
each individual object can keep track of all its own information,
每个单独的对象可以跟踪它自己的所有信息
like its position, or anything else that's relevant to it.
比如它的位置 或者任何其他与它相关的东西
We'll be talking about hit boxes today, predominantly,
今天我们将讨论热门话题 主要是
in the context of box collision, because we'll
在盒子碰撞的情况下 因为我们将
be talking about Pong, which is just paddles and a ball.
说的是乒乓球 它只是一个球拍和一个球
Those are all rectangles.
这些都是长方形
And they'll be colliding with what's called axis aligned bound--
它们将与所谓的轴对齐边界相撞--
axis aligned bounding boxes, which makes calculating whether two boxes collided
轴对齐的边界框 这使得计算两个框是否碰撞
very simple, as opposed to calculating rotated hit boxes,
非常简单 与计算旋转命中框相反
which is a bit more complicated.
这就有点复杂了
And then, lastly, we'll polish off with sound effects,
然后 最后 我们将用音效来打磨
because adding that polished layer, in my opinion, is important
因为在我看来 添加抛光层很重要
and it ties it all together and makes it feel like a more cohesive whole.
它将所有这些联系在一起 让它感觉像一个更有凝聚力的整体
So two important things that we'll need to do when we're following along
所以当我们继续下去的时候 我们需要做两件重要的事情
with the examples, which I'll show you a link to the repo in a moment,
下面是示例 稍后我将向您展示回购的链接
is getting LOVE 2D installed.
就是安装Love 2D
It's a very simple process.
这是一个非常简单的过程
The first link here is just a download link.
这里的第一个链接只是一个下载链接
So it's available for all major operating systems.
因此 它适用于所有主流操作系统
So Linux, Mac, and Windows.
因此 Linux、Mac和Windows都是如此
And then the Getting Started link down here below
然后点击下面的入门链接
will give you some tips as to how to get started,
将给你一些关于如何开始的小贴士
actually running it on your machine on Mac, iAlias,
在你的Mac iAlias上的机器上运行它
the actual runtime executable within the app that it comes with.
它附带的应用程序中的实际运行时可执行文件
So in my bash profiles that I can easily just type love space
所以在我的个人资料中 我可以很容易地输入Love space
dot in any directory that has a main dot Lua file,
任何包含主Dot Lua文件的目录中的Dot
and I can run it anywhere very simply.
我可以非常简单地在任何地方运行它
And there are similar instructions located on the page for other operating
页面上有类似的操作说明 供其他操作使用
systems.
系统
And this is the repo here, which has all of the source code
这是repo 里面有所有的源代码
that we'll be using today.
我们今天要用到的
And I've structured it in a series of 13 different subrepos
我把它组织成一系列13种不同的传票
so that you can follow along and we can build upon Pong starting from scratch,
这样你就可以跟随我们的脚步 我们可以从头开始在Pong的基础上发展
going all the way to a fully implemented game.
一直走到一个完全实现的游戏
So the first thing we'll talk about is what Lua is.
所以我们首先要谈的是Lua是什么
We'll be using Lua for about 75% of the course.
我们将在课程的75%时间里使用Lua
It's a very popular dynamic scripting language.
它是一种非常流行的动态脚本语言
Portuguese for moon, and it was invented in the early 90s
葡萄牙语是月亮的意思 它是在90年代初发明的
as primarily a config language and a runtime language
作为主要的配置语言和运行时语言
for compiled code bases to save time on adding code to those code bases
用于编译的代码库 以节省将代码添加到这些代码库的时间
and recompiling them.
并重新编译它们
A lot faster and a lot easier, especially in the context
更快、更容易 尤其是在
of the 90s when computers were much slower, to expose
90年代计算机速度慢得多的时候 要曝光
the core functionality of your application to Lua so that you can just
将您的应用程序的核心功能添加到Lua 这样您就可以
run it dynamically and then interact with your compiled code on the fly,
动态运行它 然后与您的已编译代码动态交互
rather than having to recompile and wait minutes,
而不是重新编译和等待几分钟
potentially hours, just to get some new behavior.
可能是几个小时 只是为了获得一些新的行为
It's a language that's focused around the concept of a table.
它是一种专注于表的概念的语言
Almost everything in Lua aside from basic variables, are tables.
除了基本变量之外 Lua中几乎所有的东西都是表
A table is essentially a dictionary in Python or an object in JavaScript.
表在本质上是一个在Python语言中的词典或一个在JavaScript中的对象
Very similar.
非常相似
Intent, for embedded use in larger applications,
Intent 用于在更大的应用程序中嵌入使用
and the very nature of Lua intended to be
而Lua的本质就是想要
used in the context of these large applications
在这些大型应用程序的上下文中使用
meant that it was perfect for interacting with game engines.
这意味着它非常适合与游戏引擎交互
Because game engines are a perfect example of code bases
因为游戏引擎是代码库的完美例子
that are traditionally compiled code for speed purposes.
这些代码传统上是出于速度目的而编译的代码
But it can be very cumbersome to have to add minor functionality,
但必须添加次要功能可能会非常麻烦
and then recompile it and potentially have your whole studio take hours.
然后重新编译 可能会让整个工作室花费几个小时
So we'll be using Lua and a compiled game framework, LOVE 2D,
所以我们将使用Lua和一个编译的游戏框架Love 2D
to allow us to rapidly develop.
让我们能够快速发展
It's similar to JavaScript and Python.
它类似于JavaScript和Python
A little bit more so to JavaScript.
对于JavaScript来说 情况更是如此
And it's very excellent because it was initially
它非常出色 因为它最初是
intended as a config language, and a-- just sort of a glue layer.
旨在作为一种配置语言 以及--只是一种粘合层
It's very good for storing data and code together, almost one in the same.
它非常适合将数据和代码存储在一起 几乎一个都在同一个位置
So LOVE 2D is a fast 2D game develop--
所以Love 2D是一个快速的2D游戏开发--
development framework.
开发框架
It's compiled in C++ and it runs very efficiently.
它是用C++编译的 运行效率非常高
Because it's so simple, despite the fact that we're running it in Lua,
因为它是如此简单 尽管我们在卢阿州运行它
and as modules for basically anything you
基本上可以作为你所有东西的模组
would need in the context of 2D game development.
将需要在2D游戏开发的背景下
Only 2D game development officially, although some people I know
只有2D游戏正式开发 尽管我认识的一些人
are working on slight little 3D experiments, but nothing official yet.
正在进行微小的3D实验 但还没有正式的结果
But it has graphics, keyboard input, math, basically, anything
但它有图形 键盘输入 数学 基本上 任何东西
you could want in the context of 2D game development.
您可能希望在2D游戏开发的环境中使用
It's completely free.
这是完全免费的
It's portable.
它是便携的
You can even run it on mobile and also the web.
你甚至可以在移动设备上运行 也可以在网络上运行
And it's excellent for prototyping, even if you don't necessarily
而且它非常适合原型制作 即使你不一定
want to publish a game in LOVE 2D, it's great and easy and fast just
想要在爱情2D中发布一款游戏 它很棒 简单快捷
to whip something up in LOVE 2D, and then port
在爱的2D中制造一些东西 然后搬家
that over to whatever framework or engine
无论是哪种框架或引擎
you might be using in the real world.
你可能会在现实世界中用到
So before we get into looking at some actual concrete code,
因此 在我们开始研究一些实际的具体代码之前
I think the most fundamental thing we should take a look at
我认为我们应该看一看最基本的事情
is what a game loop is.
是什么叫游戏循环
So a game, fundamentally, is just an infinite loop, like a while true or a
因此 从根本上说 游戏只是一个无限循环 就像一段时间真或一段时间
while one.
只有一次
Only in this case, every iteration of that loop we're doing a set of steps
只是在这种情况下 循环的每一次迭代我们都在执行一组步骤
back to back over and over again.
一次又一次的背靠背
We're processing input so we're seeing, has the user pressed
我们正在处理输入 所以我们正在查看 让用户按下
a key on the keyboard, have they touched their joystick,
键盘上的一个键 他们摸过他们的操纵杆了吗
have they moved the mouse, clicked the mouse.
他们有没有移动鼠标 点击鼠标
If they have, we need to feed that into our update.
如果他们有 我们需要将其添加到我们的更新中
We need to keep track of that, and then change anything in our game state
我们需要跟踪这一点 然后更改游戏状态中的任何内容
that relies upon that input.
这依赖于这种投入
So we should move our paddles, we should detect collision,
所以我们应该移动我们的球拍 我们应该检测碰撞
we should register all of this, and then whatever has updated,
我们应该把所有这些都登记下来 然后无论更新了什么
we want to rerender that.
我们想重现这一点
We want to render it--
我们想要呈现它--
render where it's changed so that we have the--
在它改变的地方渲染 这样我们就有了--
we see on our screen, visually, that things have actually
我们在屏幕上看到 在视觉上 东西实际上
changed in our game world and we interact with it,
改变了我们的游戏世界 我们与之互动
and we get a sense that we're using something,
我们有一种感觉 我们正在使用某种东西
interacting with something dynamic.
与一些动态的东西互动
And in the context of 2D games, the most fundamental way of looking at the world
在2D游戏的背景下 看待世界的最基本方式
is via the 2D coordinate system, which is just simply
是通过2D坐标系 这只是简单地
as we learned in geometry in high school, x and y-axis.
就像我们在高中学的几何学一样 x轴和y轴
In this case, it's slightly different than what we typically learn.
在这种情况下 它与我们通常所学的略有不同
In high school, we tend to learn that the xy origins, sort of bottom left,
在高中 我们倾向于学习XY起源 有点左下角的意思
y positive goes up, negative goes down, positive x goes right,
正数向上 负数向下 正x向右
and negative x goes left.
负x向左
But in this case, we're actually starting in the top left,
但在这种情况下 我们实际上是从左上角开始
and then it goes y positive down, y negative up, x positive right,
然后y正向下 y负向上 x正向右
x negative left.
X负数左转
And everything that we want to draw in our game
以及我们想要在游戏中画出的所有东西
needs to have an x and y-coordinate to draw in order
需要有x和y坐标才能按顺序绘制
for it to be visually seen on the screen.
以便在屏幕上直观地看到它
So today's goal, we're going to start a fairly low level
所以今天的目标是 我们将从一个相当低的水平开始
and work our way up through examples today and in future classes.
并通过今天和未来的课堂上的例子来提升我们的能力
Our first game is arguably one of the simplest,
我们的第一场比赛可以说是最简单的比赛之一
but also, one of the most famous games of all time, Pong,
而且 有史以来最著名的游戏之一 乒乓球
which was released in 1972.
这部电影于1972年发行
And the gist of Pong is you have a paddle
乒乓球的要点是你有一把球拍
on the left side of the screen, a paddle on the right side of the screen,
在屏幕的左侧 在屏幕的右侧有一个桨
whoever scores 10 points by getting the ball past their opponent's paddle
无论谁把球传过对手的球拍得10分
onto the edge of the screen, wins.
在屏幕的边缘 赢了
And so today in our lecture, the scope is we want to, first and foremost,
所以今天在我们的演讲中 范围是我们想要 最重要的
draw shapes to the screen, because that's how we get our ball and-- ball
在屏幕上画出形状 因为这是我们获得球和球的方式
and paddles rendering.
和划桨渲染
And those are just simply rectangles.
而这些只是简单的矩形
We want to control the 2D position of these paddles,
我们想要控制这些球拍的2D位置
because we want them to move up and down and want the ball to also move.
因为我们想要他们上下移动 希望球也能移动
We want to detect collision between the paddles and the ball,
我们想要检测球拍和球之间的碰撞
because that's how we get the ball to deflect off the paddles,
因为这是我们让球偏离球拍的方法
and to deflect off the ceiling and the floor.
并偏离天花板和地板
And, also, how we detect whether it's gone beyond the edges of the screen,
还有 我们如何检测它是否超出了屏幕的边缘
such that one player scores a point.
这样一位选手就能得一分
And then we want to add sound effects for sort of a feedback
然后我们想要添加音效 以获得某种反馈
and sort of put ourselves into the game a little bit more.
把我们自己更多地投入到游戏中
And then scorekeeping, because ultimately the purpose of the game
然后是记分 因为比赛的最终目的
is to beat your opponent, so you want a way
就是打败你的对手 所以你想要一种方法
to see who has scored 10 points first.
看看谁先得了10分
And so we're going to look through a set of examples now in the repo.
因此 我们现在将在回购中查看一组示例
If we look at Pong Zero, I've set this to be called, The Day Zero Update.
如果我们看一下Pong Zero 我已经将其命名为Day Zero更新
It's a trend among many games to have the games release major content
在许多游戏中 让游戏发布主要内容是一种趋势
updates as the x update.
随着x的更新而更新
So just to be cute, I think we'll call each individual example here,
所以为了搞笑 我想我们把每个例子都叫在这里
The Something Update.
《某事更新》
And so I'm going to go into the Pong Zero
所以我要走进Pong Zero
Repo of the directory, the GitHub repo.
目录的repo 即GitHub repo
And if we're looking at Pong Zero here, we can see it
如果我们看的是Pong Zero 我们可以看到它
says here, The Day Zero Update.
这里写着 零日更新
I've commented everything fairly heavily so that we can--
我对每一件事都做了相当认真的评论 这样我们就可以--
if you're reading the code, you can sort of get a sense of what's going on.
如果您正在阅读代码 您可以在某种程度上了解正在发生的事情
At line 23, we're going to start off by just declaring
在第23行 我们将从声明开始
a window width and a window height.
窗口宽度和窗口高度
And these are just constant variables that
这些都是恒定的变量
will be accessible throughout the rest of our application.
在我们应用程序的其余部分中都可以访问
So I'm just setting 1280 by 720 as an arbitrary resolution.
因此 我只是将1280x720设置为任意分辨率
It doesn't matter too much.
这没什么大不了的
An important thing that we need to look at here is that line 29,
我们需要注意的一件重要的事情是第29行
we're using a function called love.load, and I'm actually
我们使用的是一个名为love.Load的函数 而我实际上
going to go back to the slides here.
现在我们回到幻灯片上
We're going to look at a few functions, and I'm
我们将介绍几个函数 我将
going to go over them and just sort of tell you
我会把它们看一遍 然后告诉你
what they do before we look at the code in too much detail.
在我们详细查看代码之前 它们会做些什么
So love.load is just a function that-- given to us by LOVE, LOVE 2D,
Load只是一个函数--由Love Love 2D
and we overwrite it.
然后我们改写它
We give it behavior, we tell it what to do.
我们给它行为 我们告诉它该做什么
And LOVE 2D is going to look at it in our main.lua file.
Love 2D将在我们的main.lua文件中查看它
If we're looking at Pong Zero, you'll see it just has a main.lua file.
如果我们正在查看Pong Zero 您将看到它只有一个main.lua文件
LOVE 2D expects just a main.lua file, and will run the main.lua file,
Love 2D只需要一个main.lua文件 并将运行main.lua文件
and you can reference any other file within the directory from that main.lua
并且您可以从该main.lua引用目录中的任何其他文件
file.
文件
It's our bootstrap, effectively.
实际上 这是我们的自力更生
We're going to override love.load with whatever
我们要用任何东西来替代Love.Load
we want to execute at the very beginning of our application.
我们希望在应用程序的最开始执行
It's just a startup function.
这只是一个启动功能
We can also define all that behavior outside of the function above it,
我们还可以定义上面的函数之外的所有行为
but it's good practice to find it within love.load
但在love.load中找到它是一个很好的做法
so that someone reading your code will know,
以便阅读您的代码的人知道
OK, this is where all the startup code takes place.
好的 这是所有启动代码发生的地方
Love.update(dt) is a very important function.
更新(DT)是一个非常重要的函数
This function takes in a variable called (dt).
该函数接受一个名为(Dt)的变量
Love passes it in a function.
爱在一个函数中传递它
You're going to overwrite it with your own behavior,
你会用你自己的行为来覆盖它
and Love is going to execute this every frame, passing it in delta time,
爱将在每一帧中执行它 在增量时间内传递它
and you can use delta time (dt) in that function
您可以在该函数中使用增量时间(DT
to change your application based upon how much time has passed.
根据经过的时间更改您的应用程序
(dt) will always be a fraction of a second, potentially more,
(Dt)将始终是零点几秒 可能更多
depending on how slow your computer is.
这取决于您的计算机有多慢
But, typically, one-sixtieth of a second.
但通常是六十分之一秒
And you can scale anything in your game by that amount
你可以将游戏中的任何东西都按这个数值进行缩放
to get even behavior across all frame rates.
以在所有帧速率上获得均匀的行为
Love.draw is the other big function amongst--
Love.DRAW是其中的另一个重要功能--
between update and draw.
在更新和绘制之间
Two of the two, arguably, most important functions.
可以说 这两个功能中的两个是最重要的功能
Love.draw is the function that we're going
Love.Drawing是我们要使用的函数
to define that has all of our drawing behavior, our rendering behavior in it.
定义有我们所有的绘制行为 我们的渲染行为在其中
And that's where we can draw our paddles, we can draw our ball.
这就是我们可以画球拍的地方 我们可以画球
And then update is where we can like change
然后更新是我们可以喜欢变化的地方
the paddles position and so forth.
划桨的位置等等
Two more important functions we'll take a look at in the first example.
我们将在第一个示例中查看两个更重要的函数
Love.graphics.printf is the LOVE 2D analog of printf and C. The difference
Print tf是print tf和C的Love 2D类比
being that this printf lets us actually draw physically
因为这张照片能让我们实际地画出来
onto the screen versus a console.
屏幕上 而不是控制台上
We give it a text as a string, and an x and a y-coordinate and, optionally,
我们给它一个字符串形式的文本 以及一个x和y坐标 还可以选择
a width and an align, and it'll will draw the text at xy,
宽度和对齐 它将在xy处绘制文本
but it will also take into consideration the width,
但它也会考虑到宽度
and it'll also take in consideration the align.
它还将考虑到Align
The with is how much to align it, and the align is the mode of alignment.
With是要对齐的量 Align是对齐的模式
So if we say x is zero width, our window width, and then we say align center,
所以如果我们说x是零宽度 我们的窗口宽度 然后我们说居中对齐
it's going to go between zero and our window width and center align it.
它将在零和我们的窗口宽度之间移动 并居中对齐
So that'll have the effect of center aligning our text.
这将产生居中对齐我们的文本的效果
But we can just as easily say, right, and it will right
但我们可以很容易地说 对 它就会对
align it between those two and have the effect
在这两者之间对齐 就会产生这样的效果
of rendering the screen-- rendering the text
渲染屏幕--渲染文本
along the right edge of the screen.
沿着屏幕的右边缘
And then lastly, love.window.setmode takes a width and a height
最后 love.window.setmode获取一个宽度和一个高度
and some optional parameters.
和一些可选参数
Those parameters being things like V sync and full screen,
这些参数是垂直同步和全屏
and will actually set up our window and get it rendering onto the screen.
并将实际设置我们的窗口并将其渲染到屏幕上
And so if we go back to our source code here, it-- at line 29,
所以如果我们回到这里的源代码 它--在第29行
we're overwriting love.load.
我们正在覆盖love.load
We're passing in love.window.setmode, window width and window
我们传入了love.window.setmode、窗口宽度和窗口
height, which recall we defined up above as 1280 by 720.
高度 我们将其定义为1280乘以720
We're passing in a table.
我们路过一张桌子
This is the syntax for a table, these curly brackets.
这是表格的语法 这些花括号
And the way that we define keys and values is just with an equal sign
我们定义键和值的方式就是用等号
therein.
在那里
So full screen gets false, resizeable gets false, V sync gets true.
所以全屏显示为假 可调整大小显示为假 垂直同步显示为真
So it's going to not be full screen, it's
所以不会是全屏的 它是
going to be a not resizeable but it is going to be
将是不可调整大小的 但它将是
synced to our monitor's refresh rate.
同步到我们监视器的刷新率
And that's where V sync is, short for vertical sync.
这就是垂直同步的地方 垂直同步的简称
And then on line 40, we're overwriting love.draw,
然后在第40行 我们覆盖了Love 绘制
and this has the love.graphics.printf function, they're in,
这里有love.graph ics.print tf函数 它们在
and we're saying-- we're passing in the string, hello, Pong.
我们在说--我们正在传递字符串 你好 Pong
We're starting it at x zero, we're setting it
我们从x0开始 我们正在设置它
at y window height divided by 2, minus 6.
在y窗口高度除以2减去6
Because the default font size in LOVE 2D is 12 pixels tall.
因为Love 2D的默认字体大小是12像素高
So we're shifting it up by six so it's perfectly
所以我们把它提前了6点 所以它是完美的
centered vertically in the screen.
在屏幕上垂直居中
And then we're setting the alignment amount, the width, to window width
然后我们将对齐量、宽度设置为窗口宽度
so that it's going to align it within the entire width of our window.
这样它就会在我们窗口的整个宽度内对齐它
And now we're setting it to center alignment.
现在我们将其设置为中心对齐
So it's going to be center aligned within our entire window
因此它将在我们的整个窗口内居中对齐
starting at x zero.
从x0开始
And so if we go to Pong zero, and then we actually run it,
所以如果我们去Pong Zero 然后我们实际运行它
it has the effect of doing this.
它有这样做的效果
We're just rendering in our default font, default size,
我们只是使用默认字体、默认大小进行渲染
hello, Pong, right in the middle of the screen.
你好 Pong 就在屏幕中央
So not a terribly exciting example, but it
所以不是一个非常令人兴奋的例子 但它
is showcasing the most important functions of LOVE 2D,
正在展示LOVE 2D最重要的功能
so that we can get started with slightly more interesting examples.
这样我们就可以从稍微有趣的例子开始
So, our first content update, is the Low-Res Update.
所以 我们的第一个内容更新是低分辨率更新
So we're developing Pong and Pong is an old game.
所以我们正在开发乒乓球 而乒乓球是一项古老的游戏
It doesn't look like the example that we just looked
它看起来不像我们刚才看到的例子
at where the font is fairly high res.
字体分辨率相当高的地方
We want something that looks a little more retro.
我们想要一些看起来更复古的东西
So what we want to do is get our resolution
所以我们想要做的是得到我们的解决方案
looking like it's from a game released in 1972.
看起来像是1972年发布的一款游戏
So what we're going to do is look at a few more important functions here.
所以我们要做的是看看这里更重要的几个函数
So Pong One has these functions.
所以Pong One具有这些功能
So love.graphics.setDefaultFilter.
所以love.graph ics.setDefaultFilter
This function, the purpose of that, is every time
这个函数 那个函数的目的是每次
we have a font or an image in our application,
我们的应用程序中有一个字体或图像
it's going to be applied a filter by default.
默认情况下 它将应用于筛选器
So it's going to by default a bilinear filter.
默认情况下 它将使用双线性过滤器
So what's going to happen, the effect of that
那么会发生什么 它的影响是什么
is, basically, whenever we magnify or downscale a texture,
基本上 每当我们放大或缩小纹理时
it's going to think that-- it's going to assume
它会认为--它会假设
that we want it to be slightly blurred so as to not look too pixilated.
我们希望它稍微模糊一点 这样看起来就不会太像素化了
Which is good in certain contexts.
这在某些情况下是好的
For higher res 2D game development, that's good, but as we're going to see,
对于更高分辨率的2D游戏开发 这很好 但正如我们将看到的那样
that's not particularly good in the context of retro games.
这在复古游戏的背景下并不是特别好
Retro games have a very 2D, crisp, pixilated aesthetic,
复古游戏有非常2D的 清晰的 像素化的美学
and we want to preserve that.
我们想要保留这一点
And so this lets us set a default filter.
因此 这让我们可以设置默认过滤器
We'll see that in usage shortly.
我们很快就会看到它的用法
Another important-- very important function which is the input phase
另一个重要的--非常重要的功能是输入阶段
of our game loop that we saw earlier, love.keypressed(key) is what's going
在我们前面看到的游戏循环中 love.key(Key)是正在进行的
to allow us to start interacting with that aspect of our game.
让我们开始与游戏的这一方面互动
So love.keypressed(key) is a callback function that LOVE expects in main.lua.
因此 Love在main.lua中使用的是一个回调函数love.keypresded(Key)
We're going to overwrite it.
我们要覆盖它
It gets passed in a key, and this function
它被传递到一个键中 该函数
gets called every time by LOVE 2D whenever we press a key.
每当我们按下一个键时 就会被Love 2D呼叫
It'll detect a key pressed, and it will call this function.
它将检测到按下的键 并调用此函数
Whatever we've defined in here, it will call it,
无论我们在这里定义了什么 它都会这样称呼它
and we can set it to take in certain keys
我们可以将其设置为接受特定的键
and perform certain operations on that input and it will get a string.
并对该输入执行某些操作 它将获得一个字符串
So if we say-- if we press the escape key,
所以如果我们说--如果我们按下退出键
key is going to be equal to the string escape in that function,
键将等于该函数中的字符串转义
and we have access to that.
我们有权访问它
And another important function, love.event.quit.
还有另一个重要的函数love.vent.Quit
This has just a very simple effect of quitting the application,
这只有一个非常简单的效果 即退出应用程序
though we can call it in the code as opposed to doing it ourselves.
尽管我们可以在代码中调用它 而不是自己做
And so here's an example of what texture filtering looks like.
下面是一个纹理过滤的例子
Point filtering is the same as nearest neighbor
点过滤与最近邻点过滤相同
filtering, which is what we're going to be using.
过滤 这就是我们将要使用的
Bilinear filtering is shown on the right, where it looks pretty blurry.
右侧显示的是双线性过滤 它看起来非常模糊
That's what LOVE 2D applies by default to both fonts and to textures.
这就是Love 2D默认应用于字体和纹理的方式
And we'll see that in an example.
我们将在一个例子中看到这一点
I can actually run it in two different styles.
我实际上可以用两种不同的风格来运行它
So if you go to Pong One in the repo, and then we run it,
所以如果你去回购的Pong One 然后我们运行它
we see here, hello, Pong is now blown up.
我们看到这里 你好 乒乓球现在被炸了
And we'll look at some more code, actually,
实际上 我们会看一些更多的代码
to see as to why it's blown up.
看看它为什么会被炸毁
But if we go back to our code, let me pull up Pong One.
但如果我们回到我们的代码 让我启动Pong One
Go to main.lua, and then I'm going to explain this in just a second,
转到Main Lua 然后我马上就解释一下
but let me comment this out and we'll see the difference here.
但让我注释掉这一点 我们将在这里看到区别
You can see it looks a lot blurrier.
你可以看到它看起来模糊多了
And that's the default texture filtering taking place.
这是默认的纹理过滤
It applies, like I said, not only to textures but also to fonts.
就像我说的 它不仅适用于纹理 也适用于字体
And that's not the aesthetic we want.
而这并不是我们想要的美学
So let's look at Pong One in detail, starting at the top.
因此 让我们从顶部开始 详细了解一下Pong One
On line 28, we're acquiring a library.
在第28行 我们正在收购一个图书馆
This is how you get a library in your LOVE 2D
这就是你如何在你的爱情2D中获得一个图书馆
application, or your LOVE application.
申请 或者你的爱情申请
Just equals require and the name of the library.
只需与库的名称相等即可
Push is what we're going to be using to take our 1280 by 720 window
我们将使用推送来获取1280 x 720窗口
and turn it into a virtual resolution window at 432 by 243.
并将其变成432×243的虚拟分辨率窗口
We can start to think of our game in terms of a more low res feel,
我们可以开始从更低分辨率的角度来看待我们的比赛
and think about it in 432 by 243 pixels, but still render it
并以432 x 243像素进行思考 但仍将其渲染
in a window that's arbitrarily sized.
在一个任意大小的窗口中
In this case, we're preserving the 1280 by 720 window that we saw before.
在本例中 我们保留了以前看到的1280x720的窗口
If you go to our love.load function, we see this being used on line 47.
如果您转到love.load函数 我们会看到在第47行使用了这个函数
Instead of love.window.setmode, we're now
我们现在不是love.window.setmode 而是
using push setup screen, the push libraries setup screen function,
使用推送设置屏幕、推送库设置屏幕功能
where it takes a virtual width, a virtual height, our regular window
它需要一个虚拟的宽度 一个虚拟的高度 我们的常规窗口
width and our window height, and then the same table as before.
宽度和我们的窗口高度 然后是和以前一样的表
And this has the effect of setting up a window that's
这样做的效果是设置了一个窗口
got our concrete dimensions of 1280 by 720,
得到了1280乘720的具体尺寸
but a virtual resolution of 432 by 243.
而是432x243的虚拟分辨率
And so now, when it renders, as we'll see shortly, as--
所以现在 当它呈现时 就像我们很快会看到的那样
well, as we already did see, actually, it's magnified.
嗯 正如我们已经看到的 实际上 它被放大了
It has the effect of giving us a lower resolution.
它的效果是给我们一个较低的分辨率
And in line--on line 58, if we look at the love.keypressed function,
在第58行 如果我们看一下love.key按下的函数
we've put in there, if the key equals the string escape,
我们放在那里 如果键等于字符串转义
then love.event.quit.
然后是爱 事件 退出
So now we have input handling.
所以现在我们有了输入处理
We've overridden love.keypressed(key), which LOVE 2D is going to look
我们已经覆盖了Love 按下键(Key) 这是Love 2D将会看到的
for in our application, and then call as needed.
在我们的应用程序中 然后根据需要调用
And then we're just looking in there.
然后我们只是往里面看
If the key is escape, then love.event.quit.
如果关键字是退出 那么就是love.vent.Quit
And if I run the application, I can now press escape on my keyboard
如果我运行这个应用程序 我现在可以按键盘上的Ess键
and just quit it and not have to command quit or click
只需退出它 而不必命令退出或点击
the X on a Windows application.
Windows应用程序上的X
And we've changed one more thing, also, in the love.draw function on line 70.
我们还更改了另外一件事 在第70行的love.Draw函数中
We're using the push library now.
我们现在正在使用推送库
We need to-- it functions sort of as a state machine in that we
我们需要--它的功能有点像状态机 因为我们
set it to start rendering at a virtual resolution with push
将其设置为使用推送以虚拟分辨率开始渲染
apply start, and then push apply end, and then anything in between,
应用开始 然后按应用结束 然后应用之间的任何内容
this is very similar actually to how Open Go works.
这实际上与Open Go的工作原理非常相似
We won't go into too much detail.
我们不会涉及太多细节
But this is very similar in spirit to how much of Open Go programming works.
但这在精神上与Open Go编程的效果非常相似
Push apply start, push apply end.
按应用开始 按应用结束
Between that, whatever we call, is going to render at this virtual resolution.
在这两者之间 无论我们称之为什么 都将以这个虚拟分辨率进行渲染
And so we are calling the same love.graphics.print(f) function,
因此 我们调用相同的love.graph ics.print(F)函数
hello Pong Zero, virtual high divided by two minus six.
你好 零点乒乓球 虚拟高度除以2减6
Same parameters.
相同的参数
And it has the effect of rendering everything that's still got
它的效果是渲染仍然存在的一切
the old aliasing going on the skin--
皮肤上的旧别名--
texture filtering going on as the effect of giving us our magnified text.
纹理过滤的效果就是让我们看到放大的文本
So same text, same size, but now our window of rendering is much smaller.
所以相同的文本 相同的大小 但现在我们的渲染窗口要小得多
So--
所以--
Any questions so far on how any of this works?
到目前为止 对这一切是如何运作的有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的
Awesome.
太棒了
So we've gotten text right into the screen, but we're nowhere close to Pong
所以我们把文本直接放到了屏幕上 但我们离Pong还差得远
yet, so the first big thing, I think, that's
然而 所以我认为第一件大事 就是
going to get us closer in that direction is what we're
让我们朝那个方向走得更近 这就是我们
going to call the rectangle update.
将调用矩形更新
So some important functions that we should look at.
所以我们应该看看一些重要的功能
Love.graphics.newFont.
Love.graph ics.newFont.
The default font, I believe, is Arial.
我相信默认字体是Arial
We don't want Arial in our application, because we want something
我们不想让Arial出现在我们的应用程序中 因为我们需要一些
that looks a little more retro.
这看起来有点复古
We want something that looks more relevant.
我们想要一些看起来更相关的东西
Love.graphics.newFont will basically take a path to a font file
NewFont基本上将采用一个指向字体文件的路径
that we have in our folder, which if you're in the Pong 2 folder,
在我们的文件夹中 如果您在Pong 2文件夹
you'll see a font.ttf file, and a size.
您将看到一个Font.ttf文件和一个大小
Because every font object that we instantiate
因为我们实例化的每个字体对象
needs to have a size, because the font objects are immutable.
需要有一个大小 因为字体对象是不变的
Once constructed, they cannot be changed so they need to be allocated on a size
一旦构建 它们就不能更改 因此需要按大小进行分配
by size basis.
按大小计算
Love.graphics.setFont will take whatever font
SetFont将采用任何字体
object we've acquired from this function call, and we can set it here
对象 我们可以在这里设置它
and it'll set the active font in LOVE 2D to be that font.
它会将Love 2D中的活动字体设置为该字体
Love is a state machine in the same sense
同样 爱情也是一台状态机
as before, in that it will have an active font at any one time,
与以前一样 它将在任何时候都具有活动字体
and whatever print functions you call, will use the currently active font.
无论您调用什么打印函数 都将使用当前活动的字体
And that also applies to whatever color you might want to render to the screen,
这也适用于您可能想要渲染到屏幕上的任何颜色
whatever.
管他呢
If you have a font and you want to maybe render it in red,
如果您有一种字体 并且想要将其呈现为红色
you need a set LOVE 2D's active color to red as well.
你也需要一套LOVE 2D的主动色到红色
Love.graphics.clear is a function that takes an RGBA quadruple,
Clear是一个接受RGBA四元组的函数
and will flush the screen in that color.
并将以该颜色刷新屏幕
It just has a simple effect of wiping the screen in that color.
它只有一个简单的效果 就是用那种颜色擦拭屏幕
Useful for drawing just flat color backgrounds.
对于仅绘制纯色背景非常有用
And then the last function, probably the most important function,
然后是最后一个功能 可能是最重要的功能
is love.graphics.rectangle.
是love.graph ics.Rectangle
And this is the first function that we'll
这是我们将使用的第一个函数
see that actually ends up drawing something beyond text to the screen.
看 这实际上是在屏幕上绘制文本以外的东西
It takes it a mode, which can be fill or line, an x and a y
它采用一种模式 可以是填充或线条、x和y
and a width and a height, and it'll draw a rectangle in that mode.
宽度和高度 它将在该模式下绘制一个矩形
So either filled, so a filled rectangle, or a line rectangle.
所以要么是实心 要么是实心矩形 要么是线条矩形
It'll take-- it'll draw it at xy with the width and the height
它会--它会用宽度和高度把它画在xy处
that we pass in.
我们把它传进去
So let's go ahead and take a look at Pong 2
那么让我们继续下去 看看乒乓球2
where we can see this actually implemented.
在那里我们可以看到这一点实际上得到了实施
So Pong 2, we have our font.ttf in there that I've included.
所以Pong 2 我们有我们的Font.ttf 我已经把它包括在内了
And then a main.lua.
然后是一条主流星
And by the way, I forgot to mention last example,
顺便说一句 我忘了提到最后一个例子
push the library that we required is also just in the same directory.
我们所需的PUSH库也在同一目录中
And you can just do require as long as the file is there within the directory,
只要文件在目录中 您就可以要求
it will just load it.
它会直接把它装上
You don't have to specify .lua.
您不必指定.lua
It assumes when you require some string, that it follows with the .lua suffix.
它假定当您需要某个字符串时 它后跟.lua后缀
So we're here looking at main.lua in Pong 2, the rectangle update.
所以我们在这里看的是Pong 2中的main.lua 矩形的更新
So on line 28 to 34, it's all the same stuff.
所以在第28行到第34行 都是一样的东西
We're acquiring push.
我们正在获得推力
We have our width and height virtually and physically.
我们在虚拟和物理上都有自己的宽度和高度
In our love.load function, we are on line 43
在love.load函数中 我们位于第43行
declaring small font to be a love.graphics.newFont,
将小字体声明为love.graph ics.newFont
giving it the path font.ttf because it's right there
将路径指定为font.ttf 因为它就在那里
in the same directory at size eight.
在同一个目录中 大小为8
And this is going to create a font object, small font, that we can then
这将创建一个字体对象 小字体 然后我们就可以
set as the active font as needed.
根据需要设置为活动字体
So if we go down to line 78 in the same directory,
因此 如果我们深入到同一目录中的第78行
we see we're calling love.graphics.clear,
我们看到我们正在调用love.graph 清楚
and so we're passing it in a color.
所以我们用一种颜色来传递它
I sampled some images of Pong on Google Images
我在谷歌图片上试用了一些乒乓球的图片
and saw a background gray that I liked, so 40, 45, 52, RGB, and then 255 just
我看到了我喜欢的背景灰色 所以40 45 52 RGB 然后255
means completely opaque, so no transparency, the alpha component.
意味着完全不透明 因此没有透明度 即Alpha分量
And then we're doing the same print.function
然后我们执行相同的打印 函数
as we did before on line 81.
就像我们之前在81号线上做的那样
Below that on line 89 down through 95, we're actually
在第89行到第95行下面 我们实际上是
calling love.graphics.rectangle.
调用love.graph ics.rectang.
And these are drawing the two paddles and then the ball.
这是画两个球拍 然后是球
So, note, love.graphics.rectangle fill mode,
所以 注意 love.graph 矩形填充模式
because we want the paddles to be completely filled, as is the ball.
因为我们希望球拍完全充满 球也是如此
We're giving it an xy of 1030 and a width height of 520.
我们给它的XY是1030 宽度高度是520
And on 992, we're-- and that'll have the effect of drawing it a little bit
在992年 我们--这会产生一点影响
shifted from the top left corner, five pixels wide, 20 pixels tall.
从左上角移动 宽5个像素 高20个像素
On line 92, we're doing the same thing, except we're
在第92行 我们在做同样的事情 除了我们
going virtual width minus 10.
实际宽度减去10
So it's going to go to the right edge of our screen, virtual width minus 10.
所以它会移到我们屏幕的右边 虚拟宽度减去10
So 432 minus 10.
所以432减去10
So 422.
所以是422
And then virtual height minus 50.
然后是虚拟身高减去50
So it's going to be slightly--
所以这将是一个轻微的--
it's going to be slightly up from the bottom of the screen.
它将从屏幕底部略微向上
So we have our top left paddle and our bottom right paddle.
所以我们有左上角和右下角的划桨
And then the ball is dead center.
然后球就在中心了
So we're sitting-- doing another graphics-- rectangle call.
所以我们坐着--做另一个图形--矩形调用
Virtual width minus two divided by two.
虚拟宽度减去2除以2
So right in the middle, minus two, because our ball
所以就在中间 减去2 因为我们的球
is going to be two pixels wide by two pixels tall.
将是两个像素宽乘以两个像素高
And same thing with virtual height, minus two.
虚拟身高也是如此 减去2
Our virtual height divided by two, minus two.
我们的虚拟身高除以2 减去2
So I'm going to go ahead and CD into the Pong 2 directory and run it.
所以我将继续CD到Pong 2目录并运行它
And that has the effect of we have our new font here in the middle.
这样的效果就是我们的新字体在中间
So it looks nice and retro, much more so than the Arial font as before.
所以它看起来很好 复古 比以前的Arial字体更好
We have a rectangle here, five pixels wide by 20 pixels tall.
我们有一个长方形 5像素宽 20像素高
A ball in the middle, which is four pixels wide by four
中间的一个球 4像素宽
pixels tall, and then a paddle on the bottom right,
像素高 右下角有一个桨
which is the same dimensions as the paddle on the left.
和左边的桨的尺寸一样
So it looks very similar to Pong.
它看起来很像Pong
It's not interactive at all, but we sort of getting the feel of what
它一点也不互动 但我们可以感觉到
we want our application to look like.
我们希望我们的应用程序看起来像
We have it mostly sketched out.
我们已经大致勾勒出来了
So any questions so far as to how this works?
有什么问题吗？
OK.
好的.
Awesome.
棒了
So Pong 3.
3.我的超能力
So currently we have no interactivity with our application,
所以目前我们还没有与我们的应用程序进行交互
and we want to be able to move the paddles around.
我们希望能够移动电极板
We don't want to just be looking at an-- at an image the whole time.
我们不想一直看着一张照片
So the paddle update is going to solve this problem for us.
因此 桨更新将为我们解决这个问题
We're going to actually get our first sort of-- beyond pressing escape
我们将得到第一种--除了按下Escape之外
to quit the application, we're going to get a sense
退出应用程序 我们将得到一个感觉
of interacting with it dynamically.
与之动态互动
So the important function that we're going to look at in this example
所以我们在这个例子中要看的重要函数
is love.keyboard.isDownsomekey.
就是love. keyboard. isDownsomeKey
And this is true-- this is a Boolean function.
这是一个布尔函数
It just returns true or false depending on whether the key that we pass in
它只是返回true或false取决于我们传入的密钥
as a string is currently pressed down on this frame.
因为一根弦现在被压在这个框架上
So it just returns true or false.
所以它只返回true或false
And so let's go ahead and take a look at the demo.
让我们来看看演示
We're going to go ahead and pull up Pong 3.
我们要继续前进 并拉上乒乓3
The main.lua, they're in.
主路阿 他们进来了
Notice that line 37 if you're looking in Pong 3 we, have a new constant
注意第37行 如果你在看乒乓球3 我们有一个新的常数
we've defined called paddle speed, which gets the value 200.
我们定义了桨速 它的值为200
And this is just an arbitrary value that I found was a good speed.
这只是一个任意的值 我发现这是一个很好的速度
But this is how fast our paddle is going to move.
但这就是我们的桨移动的速度
We're going to scale it by delta time, so we're
我们将用时间增量来衡量它
going to multiply it by how many seconds have passed.
乘以过去的秒数
Typically, a fraction of a second since the last frame.
通常 自上一帧起的几分之一秒
And this is going to, therefore, move the same distance
因此 它将移动相同的距离
over time depending on whether your computer is
随着时间的推移 这取决于您的计算机是否
running at 10 frames per second or 60 frames per second.
以每秒10帧或每秒60帧运行
So if we go down here to line 63, I've also set up two new variables.
如果我们在第63行 我也设置了两个新变量
Player one score and player two score.
一号选手得分二号选手得分
Those are both initialized at zero.
它们都初始化为零
We're going to add in this example, also, some rendering of the score.
我们将在这个例子中添加一些乐谱的渲染
And notice here on line 49, I've also added
注意在第49行 我还添加了
a new font, which showcases how you need to separate fonts based on their size
一种新的字体 它展示了如何根据字体的大小来区分字体
because they're immutable objects.
因为它们是不可变的对象
Score font gets love.graphics.newFont.
分数字体得到love.graphics.newFont.
Same exact font file, but it's 32 pixels large because the font-- or the score
完全一样的字体文件 但它是32像素大 因为字体-或分数
when rendered in Pong is pretty large in the middle of the screen.
当在Pong中渲染时 屏幕中间相当大
And so we're creating-- we have two different fonts now.
我们现在有两种不同的字体
One for rendering our message, one for rendering our score.
一个用来传递我们的信息 一个用来传递我们的分数
And it's just going to render these two variables, player one score and player
它只会呈现这两个变量 参与人1的得分和参与人
two score.
两百
And then we've also initialized our y values
然后我们也初始化了y值
for the rectangles, the paddles on the left and the right.
对于长方形 左边和右边的桨
We need to keep track of their y position, because paddles in Pong
我们需要跟踪他们的y位置 因为乒乓球中的球拍
can only move up or down.
只能上下移动
So player 1Y gets the same value it did before when
所以参与人1 Y得到的值和之前一样
we initialized the rectangle, when we drew it onto the screen.
当我们把矩形画到屏幕上时 我们初始化了它
It's going to start at y 30, so pretty high up.
它将从30日元开始 所以相当高
And player 2y is going to start pretty low, virtual height
参与人2 y从很低的虚拟高度开始
minus 50, which is 432 minus 50.
减去50 也就是432减去50
And so in love.update, which is our first actual use of the update
所以在爱.更新 这是我们第一次实际使用的更新
function on line 75 with the (dt) parameter that gets passed in.
第75行的函数 带有传入的（dt）参数
Note, remember that LOVE 2D will pass that in for us,
请注意 记住 爱2D将为我们传递
but we need to give it-- we need to define the behavior inside of it.
但我们需要给它--我们需要定义它里面的行为
We're using love.keyboard.isDown, and we're passing in the string w
我们使用love.keyboard.isDown 并传入字符串w
and s for this first block.
S为这第一个街区
This first block here is player one's movement.
这里的第一个块是一号选手的动作
So, traditionally, on computer WASD is to move--
所以 传统上 在计算机上WASD是移动的--
and this example, we're going to allow ourselves to move both paddles,
在这个例子中 我们将允许我们自己移动两个球拍
so we're going to use w and s for the left paddle,
因此 我们将使用w和S作为左桨
and up or down for the right paddle.
然后向上或向下划向右划桨
So if love.keyboard.isDown w, which means--
所以如果love.keyboard.isDown w 这意味着--
or we've currently pressing the W key, player 1y
或者我们现在正在按W键 玩家1Y
is going to get itself, plus negative paddle speed times delta time.
等于它自己 加上负的划桨速度乘以增量时间
So it's going to move up.
所以它会向上移动
It's going to take negative paddle speed, multiply it by delta time,
它将采用负的划桨速度 乘以增量时间
and add that onto our y value, which will have
然后把它加到我们的y值上 它将会有
the effect of shifting our paddle up.
把我们的球拍向上移动的效果
And it's the opposite for--
而事实恰恰相反--
on line 82 for-- if we're pressing the s key.
在82行--如果我们按S键
We need to increase the y by positive paddle speed, because recall,
我们需要以正的划桨速度来增加y 因为回想一下
y-axis movement is--
Y轴运动是--
up is negative, down is positive.
上涨是负数 下跌是正数
We're doing the exact same thing with the paddle on the right
我们用右边的球拍做同样的事情
except we're using up and down as the strings into love.keyboard.isDown.
只是我们使用UP和DOWN作为love.keyboard.isDown的字符串
And then down below here, we are rendering in addition
然后在下面的下面 我们正在渲染另外
to what we rendered before, also, the score now.
我们之前呈现的东西 现在也是比分
So on line 125, note that we're calling love.graphics.setFont, scoreFont,
因此在第125行 请注意我们调用的是love.graph ics.setFont Scott Font
because if we don't call this, it will use just whatever the last font was,
因为如果我们不调用它 它将使用上一种字体
which by default is the eight pixel font because we set that
默认情况下是8像素字体 因为我们设置了
up top in our program.
在我们的节目中排在首位
We want to set it to the score font, and then we
我们希望将其设置为乐谱字体 然后我们
want to call love.graphics.print.
我想调用love.graph ics.print
In this case, I'm just printing them in concrete places not, using printf.
在本例中 我只是在具体的地方打印它们 而不是使用printf
Virtual width divided by two minus 50.
虚拟宽度除以2减去50
So no matter how we scale our window, it's
因此 无论我们如何调整窗口 它都是
always going to be 50 pixels to the left of the center of the window,
始终是窗口中心左侧的50个像素
and the 30 pixels to the right of the center of the window
和窗口中心右侧的30个像素
if we're rendering the player two score.
如果我们给玩家两分的话
And so if we go into Pong 3 and we run it, it looks the same as before.
因此 如果我们进入Pong 3并运行它 它看起来和以前一样
Note, that we do have a score now in the middle of the screen, zero and zero.
请注意 我们现在在屏幕中间有一个分数 0和0
But, more importantly, we can move our paddles up and down.
但是 更重要的是 我们可以上下移动我们的球拍
But there's one problem, and that's I can move beyond the edge of the screen,
但有一个问题 那就是我可以移动到屏幕边缘之外
which is not behavior that we want in our application.
这不是我们在应用程序中想要的行为
So we have some interactivity, it's moving along,
所以我们有一些互动 它在向前发展
but we still have a long way to go, unfortunately.
但不幸的是 我们还有很长的路要走
Or fortunately.
或者幸运的是
So let's go ahead and look at the ball update.
所以让我们继续来看看球的最新情况
So we have paddles, they can move, they can move beyond the edge of the screen,
所以我们有了桨 它们可以移动 它们可以移动到屏幕边缘之外
but we don't have a ball that-- it just sits in the middle of the screen.
但是我们没有一个球--它只是坐在屏幕的中央
And that's not what we're looking for.
这不是我们要找的
We want to have a ball that we can actually bounce between the paddles
我们想要一个可以在球拍之间弹跳的球
so we can get an actual game going beyond just moving paddles.
这样我们就可以得到一场真正的游戏 而不仅仅是移动球拍
So a few important functions we're going to look at.
所以我们要看几个重要的函数
We're going to get our first look here at random.
我们将在这里随机第一次看到
So in games, random number generation is a very common thing
所以在游戏中 随机数的产生是一件很常见的事情
so that we get unpredictability and variability between different instances
这样我们就可以在不同实例之间获得不可预测性和可变性
of our game.
在我们的比赛中
An important function that just belongs to Lua.
一个只属于Lua的重要功能
It's not a LOVE 2D thing, it's just a Lua thing.
这不是爱情2D的事情 这只是Lua的事情
Math.random seed numb.
数学 随机种子数
So many of you have probably heard of like seed,
你们中的许多人可能都听说过像种子这样的名字
like a random number generator, seed, and that just
就像一个随机数生成器 种子 这就是
means a random number generator.
表示随机数生成器
Because it's pseudo random, it needs some sort
因为它是伪随机的 所以它需要某种排序
of starting value to base all of its random numbers off of.
其所有随机数的起始值
It takes a starting number, it performs some mathematical operation
它接受一个起始数字 它执行一些数学运算
on that number to derive new random values that we can then
得出新的随机值 然后我们就可以
use in our game engine.
在我们的游戏引擎中使用
But if we give it the same number every single time,
但如果我们每次都给它相同的数字
it's just going to give us the same random numbers every single time,
它每次都会给我们相同的随机数
which means it's not going to be random at all.
这意味着它根本不会是随机的
It's going to be very consistent.
这将是非常一致的
So we need a way to seed our random number generator,
因此 我们需要一种方法来生成随机数生成器
give it a different initial value or seed,
给它一个不同的初始值或种子
and we're going to do that with the function math.randomseed somenumb.
我们将用函数数学来实现这一点 随机种子
OS.time is an important function in the context of this,
在这种情况下 时间是一个重要的函数
because a very common way of getting a different number every time
因为每次获得不同号码的一种非常常见的方法
you run your application is passing it in whatever the current time is
无论当前时间是什么时间 运行应用程序都是在传递它
in seconds, because usually it's a very large number that
几秒钟内 因为通常是一个非常大的数字
is going to be different every single time you run your game, no matter what.
无论如何 每次运行游戏时都会有所不同
Because it's based upon, in the context of most engines,
因为它的基础是 在大多数发动机的背景下
in the context of Lua, what's called Unix Epoch time, which is zero
在Lua的上下文中 所谓的Unix纪元时间是零
zero UTC January 1st, 1970, which is some huge number nine or 10 digits long
零UTC 1970年1月1日 这是一个巨大的数字 有9位或10位数长
that changes every single second.
这种情况每时每刻都在改变
And then in order to actually take advantage of all this,
然后 为了真正利用这一切
we need a function to get a random number,
我们需要一个函数来获得一个随机数
and so we do that with math.random, which takes a min and a max,
所以我们用数学 随机 它需要最小值和最大值
although you don't need to technically pass a min,
尽管从技术上讲 你不需要通过一分钟
it'll just implicitly deuse min as one if you don't pass it a min.
如果不传递min 它只会隐式地将min作为1来使用
And it'll return a value inclusively within that range.
它将返回一个包含在该范围内的值
So if you say math.random one, 50, it'll give us
所以如果你说数学 随机一 50 它会给我们
a random inclusively between 1 and 50.
介于1和50之间的随机数
And if we just say math.random 50, it'll do the same exact thing.
如果我们只说数学 随机50 它会做同样的事情
It'll say-- it'll assume rmin is one and give us a value between one and 50.
它会说 它会假设rmin为1 并给出一个介于1和50之间的值
And then two important mathematical functions
然后是两个重要的数学函数
that are very basic but helpful in the context of games almost everywhere,
这是非常基本的 但在几乎所有地方的游戏环境中都是有用的
it's just math.min, which returns the lesser of two values,
它只是math.min 它返回两个值中较小的一个
and math.max which turns the greater of two values.
和math.max 它转换两个值中较大的一个
And we'll see this in the context of clamping values to some range.
我们将在将值限制在某个范围内的情况下看到这一点
So let's go ahead and take a look at a demo here.
那么 让我们来看看这里的一个演示
So I'm going to go ahead and open up Pong 4.
所以我要继续下去 打开Pong 4
And going to look at main.lua they're in.
然后看一下Main Lua 他们进入了
So here on line 47, we see we're calling the math.random seedfunction as before.
所以在第47行 我们看到我们正在调用数学 随机种子函数 和以前一样
And note that we're passing in OS.time, another function call,
注意 我们传入的是OS time 另一个函数调用
because OS.time is going to be different every time we run our application.
因为每次运行我们的应用程序时 OS的时间都会不同
So we're seeding our application every time
所以我们每次都在播种我们的应用程序
we run it based on whatever the current second is relative to zero, zero, zero,
我们根据当前秒相对于0 0 0
zero, zero, zero, January 1st, 1970.
零 1970年1月1日
Which is going to be different every single time we run.
我们每次跑步都会有所不同
Assuming we don't run it within the same second.
假设我们不在同一秒内运行它
And then if we go down to line 71 and seven-- or, sorry, 67 and 68,
如果我们下到71号线和7号线--或者 对不起 67号线和68号线
we now have--
我们现在有了--
we're giving a starting value to our ball,
我们给我们的球一个起始值
because we want to actually start manipulating our ball.
因为我们想真正开始操控我们的球
So we give it an X and a Y. So we're setting it right to the center again
所以我们给它一个X和一个Y 所以我们再次将它放在中心位置
but, now, we're defining a variable for it
但现在 我们正在为它定义一个变量
instead of just rendering it statically with our love.graphics.rectangle
而不是用我们的Love静态地呈现它 graph 矩形
function, because we want this to change over time.
函数 因为我们希望这种情况随着时间的推移而改变
We want to start letting our ball move around the screen.
我们想开始让我们的球在屏幕上移动
So these x and y variables are going to start changing now,
所以这些x和y变量现在开始改变
and they're going to change relative to its current velocity.
它们将相对于它的当前速度发生变化
And its velocity is going to be stored in ball dx and ball dy.
它的速度将存储在球dx和球dy中
dx and dy are common shorthands for delta x and delta y,
Dx和dy是增量x和增量y的常用缩写
which is how you represent velocity.
这就是你表示速度的方式
So what we're going to do, effectively, is take whatever our delta x and delta
所以我们要做的是 有效地取我们的增量x和增量
y are and add them onto our ball frame by frame,
并将它们一帧一帧地添加到我们的球上
and that's going to have the effect of updating
这将产生更新的效果
our ball's position by some value.
我们的球的位置有一定的价值
And separating the delta x and the delta y
并将增量x和增量y分开
will allow us to have different angles, different trajectories for our ball.
会让我们的球有不同的角度 不同的轨迹
And then another thing that we're also doing in this application,
然后我们在这个应用程序中也做了另一件事
we're starting with the concept of a game state.
我们从游戏状态的概念开始
Because now we can have a starting state, and what we're going to have
因为现在我们可以有一个初始状态 以及我们将拥有的
is a play state.
是一种播放状态
And so all we're going to do here in this example
在这个例子中 我们要做的就是
and in this application is start state as a string.
在此应用程序中 启动状态为字符串
In future examples, we're going to use what's called a state machine
在未来的示例中 我们将使用所谓的状态机
and actually separate out different states into their own--
实际上把不同的州分成各自的州--
into their own modules.
放入他们自己的模块中
But in the context of this game, we're just
但在这场比赛的背景下 我们只是
going to use a simple string just to illustrate
我将使用一个简单的字符串来说明
how it works, and we're going to say our first state, when we start the game,
它是如何工作的 当我们开始游戏时 我们将说出我们的第一个状态
should be the start string in the start state.
应该是处于开始状态的开始字符串
And so here on line 86, what we're going to do
所以在第86行 我们要做的是
is solve a problem that we had in the last example, which was,
是解决我们在上一个例子中遇到的一个问题
the paddles could move beyond the edges of the screen, which is not behavior
操纵杆可能会移动到屏幕边缘之外 这不是行为
that we should permit.
这是我们应该允许的
So we're going to call math.max on zero, and the same operation
所以我们将在0上调用math.max 同样的操作
we were doing before, and that will have the effect of returning whichever
我们以前是这样做的 这将产生返回的效果 无论是哪一个
of those two values is greater.
这两个值中较大的一个
So if the value is--
因此 如果值是--
if we're adding negative paddle speed to our y value
如果我们在y值上加上负的划桨速度
and it goes into the negative range, which
它进入了负值范围 这是
means it's beyond the top edge of the screen,
意味着它超出了屏幕的顶端
zero is going to be the greater of those values
零将是这些值中较大的一个
and so it will always be zero in that case. math.max returns
所以在这种情况下 它永远是零 Math.max返回
the greater of the two values.
两个值中较大的一个
So it'll have the effect of clamping it such that it never
所以它会有夹紧它的效果 这样它就永远不会
goes above the top edge.
位于顶部边缘上方
The inverse is true for line 96, where we
第96行的情况正好相反 在这里我们
call math.min on virtual height minus 20,
对虚拟高度减去20调用math.min
and player 1.y plus paddle speed.delta-- times delta time.
选手1.y加上划桨速度 增量乘以增量时间
And this will have the same effect, it will return whichever
这将具有相同的效果 它将返回
of these two values is lesser.
这两个值中较小的一个
In which case, if we've gone above virtual height minus 20, which
在这种情况下 如果我们超过了虚拟高度减去20
is down at the bottom of the screen shifted by the size of our paddle,
在屏幕底部移动了我们的球拍的大小
it's going to set it to virtual height minus 20.
它将把它设置为虚拟高度减20
So we never go below that point.
因此 我们永远不会低于这一点
And we're doing the same thing for player two, exact same logic.
我们也在为2号玩家做同样的事情 完全相同的逻辑
And then if we're in the play state, we're
如果我们处于播放状态 我们就会
going to actually update our ball's position.
来更新我们的球的位置
So we're in the-- if we're in the start state, ball's not going to move at all.
所以我们处于--如果我们处于开始状态 球是不会移动的
But if we're in the play state, we want ball x to equal ball x plus ball
但如果我们处于播放状态 我们希望球x等于球x加球
x times delta time.
X乘以增量时间
And note that there is no shorthand in Lua
请注意 Lua中没有速记
for adding the value to itself, which is why we're calling ball
为自身增加价值 这就是为什么我们称之为Ball
x equals ball x, plus ball x times delta time,
等于球x 加上球x乘以增量时间
instead of just saying ball x plus equals ball x times delta time.
而不是简单地说球x+等于球x乘以增量时间
Just a language decision that they made.
这只是他们做出的语言决定
But if we're in the play state, this will
但如果我们处于播放状态 这将是
have the effect of scaling whatever our current ball's velocity is and--
无论我们当前的球的速度是多少 都有缩放的效果--
times delta time, so it stays frame rate independent.
乘以增量时间 因此它保持与帧速率无关
And then adding it to ball x and ball y, which will shift it.
然后把它加到球x和球y上 这会使它移位
And we get this actually working down here in line 170--
我们在这里的170行得到了实际的结果--
174.
174.
We're now-- instead of just rendering flat numbers to the screen,
我们现在--不只是在屏幕上呈现纯平的数字
we're actually using ball x and ball y to render.
我们实际上是在使用球x和球y来渲染
And if we're in the play state, those will get updated.
如果我们处于播放状态 这些将会更新
But if we go back up to line 127, now, we're in the love.keypressed function,
但如果我们回到第127行 现在 我们在Love中 按键函数
so we're starting on line 120.
所以我们从120号线开始
Before we just had the if key equals escape, then love.event.quit.
在我们刚刚有If键等于逸出之前 那么love.vent.it
But now on line 127, we're going to check
但现在在第127行 我们要检查
to see if the key is equal to enter or return,
要查看该键是否等于Enter或Return
and then we're going to use that as our way of just testing state changes.
然后我们将使用它作为我们测试状态变化的方法
So we're going to say if the game state is equal to the start,
所以我们要说 如果游戏状态等于开始
once you press entered, the game state should be equal to play.
一旦你按回车 游戏状态应该等于玩
Otherwise, set it back to start.
否则 将其重新设置为开始
And we set it back to start, we're going to re-initialize our x
我们将它设置为开始 我们将重新初始化我们的x
and y to be in the center, virtual width divided by two
和y在中心 虚拟宽度除以2
minus two, virtual height divided by two minus two,
-2 虚拟高度除以2-2
and we're going to give it an initial random starting velocity again.
我们再一次给它一个初始的随机起始速度
And note here, this math.random two equal--
注意这里 这个数学 随机二等于--
is equal to one, and 100, or negative 100.
等于1和100 或负100
It's just Lua's way of doing a ternary operation.
这只是Lua做三元运算的方式
So in C, you will often have like--
所以在C语言中 你通常会有这样的--
you would be something like math.random two equals one,
你会有点像数学 随机二等于一
and you would have a question mark, 100 colon, negative 100.
你会有一个问号 100冒号 负100
It's the same exact thing, but Lua doesn't
这是一模一样的东西 但Lua不是
have that sort of shorthand for a ternary operation, so we do it with
有三进制操作的简写 所以我们用
and and or.
和或
We use logical operations instead to do the same thing.
我们使用逻辑运算来做同样的事情
And note here we're also showcasing that math.random can take
注意这里我们也展示了数学 random可以
either one argument or two arguments.
一个参数或两个参数
In this case, we're saying math.random two,
在这种情况下 我们说的是数学 随机二
which means it will give us a value between one and two.
这意味着它会给我们一个介于1和2之间的值
So a 50-50.
所以五五分成
And then if we do negative 50-50, that means
如果我们做负50-50 那意味着
we'll get a value between negative 50 and 50.
我们会得到一个介于负50和50之间的值
So a range of 100, effectively.
所以有效范围是100
And so what that has the effect of doing, if we run our application,
如果我们运行应用程序
we go into Pong 4.
我们进入Pong 4
We're in the start state so now we're rendering--
我们在开始状态 所以现在我们渲染--
if we're in the start state, it's set to render that message.
如果我们处于开始状态 它将被设置为呈现该消息
If we press Enter, the ball gets a random veloc-- it's actually
如果我们按下回车键 球会得到一个随机的速度--实际上
applying the velocity frame by frame.
一帧一帧地应用速度
It's updating in the update method.
它在update方法中更新
If we press Enter again, it gets reset and we're back in the start state.
如果我们再次按Enter键 它将重置 我们将返回到开始状态
So we do it again, it's getting a random value.
所以我们再做一次 它得到一个随机值
Do it again, random value.
再来一次 随机值
Random value.
随机值
So every time we're getting a different random ball value.
所以每次我们得到一个不同的随机球值
But what happens if we try to actually run it, or try to interact with it?
但是如果我们试着运行它 或者试着与它互动 会发生什么呢？
Nothing.
没什么
Goes straight through.
直接穿过去
So we're missing a key piece, even though we
所以我们缺少了一个关键的部分 尽管我们
have the core components of our game engine implemented,
实现了我们游戏引擎的核心组件
we don't have any concrete game play, nothing's interacting.
我们没有任何具体的游戏 没有任何互动
And that's a major piece that we need to look at.
这是我们需要关注的一个主要部分
And so the next--
接下来
before we actually start doing that, though, we're
在我们真正开始之前
going to take a look at the class update, Pong 5.
我们来看看职业更新 乒乓5
And so in order to get into more of a-- in order
所以为了更深入地了解
to scale our code more effectively, we need
为了更有效地扩展代码 我们需要
to start looking in terms of classes.
开始从阶级的角度看问题
And instead of having an x and a y for our ball, an x and a y for our paddle,
我们的球没有x和y 我们的桨也没有x和y
a delta x, a delta y for our ball, all these different variables that
我们的球的Δ x Δ y 所有这些不同的变量
are sort of all over the place starting to bloat our code,
到处都是开始膨胀我们的代码
before we get too crazy with it, we should think about
在我们为之疯狂之前 我们应该考虑一下
how can we put this data altogether so that we can just think in terms
我们怎样才能把这些数据放在一起 这样我们就可以只考虑
of our paddles or our ball object.
我们的球拍或者我们的球体
And so we use what's called a class.
所以我们使用所谓的类
If unfamiliar, a class is simply a way of taking all these variables that
如果不熟悉 类只是一种获取所有这些变量的方法
we've been using thus far, but putting them together in a container such that
我们到目前为止一直在使用 但把它们放在一个容器里 这样
we can just say, paddle.x or paddle--
我们可以说 Paddle.x或Paddle--
you know, in this case, car.
你知道 在这种情况下 是汽车
If we have a function called drive car, now we can just say, car.drive instead.
如果我们有一个名为Drive Car的函数 现在我们只需说Car
We don't have to have functions that are separate from our values,
我们不一定要有与我们的价值观分开的功能
that-- we can put them all together.
我们可以把它们放在一起
We can ask what's our car's current mileage instead
我们可以问我们的车目前的行驶里程是多少
of having all these different variables all over the place.
所有这些不同的变量无处不在
So the classes are effectively blueprints.
因此 这些课程实际上就是蓝图
Use it-- you define a class.
使用它--定义一个类
You say, OK, my car class is going to have
你说 好吧 我的汽车课将会有
a-- it's going to have a mileage variable,
A--它会有一个里程变量
it's going to have a paint variable, it's going to have a make and a model,
它将有一个油漆变量 它将有一个品牌和一个型号
it's going to have all these things, and it's going to maintain its own state.
它将拥有所有这些东西 并将保持自己的状态
It's going to maintain all of that for us.
它将为我们保持这一切
as seen here.
如图所示
And, typically, these are what are called fields.
通常 这些就是所谓的字段
And then we'll have methods as well.
然后我们也会有方法
Functions that, instead of being like completely separate from this data,
功能 而不是完全独立于这些数据
a car now basically owns its own functions.
汽车现在基本上拥有自己的功能
It has its own method called drive, or turn, or honk, et cetera,
它有自己的方法 称为驾驶 或转向 或按喇叭 等等
and we don't need to have a function called,
我们不需要一个名为的函数
like, turn car, or honk car, et cetera.
比如 转弯 或者按喇叭等等
And then this class is effectively a blueprint.
然后这门课实际上就是一张蓝图
Well, we'll see shortly how to define a class,
好 我们很快就会看到如何定义一个类
but in order to actually have like one paddle that has its own set of data,
但为了真正像一把桨一样拥有自己的数据集
and another paddle that has its own set of data, we need to define--
我们需要定义另一个拥有自己的数据集的划桨--
we need to instantiate, create objects from this class.
我们需要从这个类实例化、创建对象
Basically, use this class as a blueprint, but take it to a factory
基本上 使用这个类作为蓝图 但将其带到工厂
and create concrete cars from the blueprint.
并根据蓝图制造混凝土汽车
And those are objects.
这些都是物件
And so as seen here, our paddles and ball
就像这里看到的 我们的球拍和球
are perfect simple use cases for doing this.
都是做这件事的完美的简单用例
So let's go ahead and take a look at Pong 5.
那么 让我们继续下去 看看乒乓球5
So in Pong 5, immediately, if you look at the directory structure,
所以在Pong 5中 立即 如果你看一下目录结构
you can see that we've added a ball.lua and a paddle.lua.
您可以看到 我们已经添加了一个球.lua和一个Paddle.lua
And it's tradition in most languages that have object oriented programming,
这是大多数面向对象编程语言的传统
as it's called, to capitalize class names just so you can differentiate
正如它所称的 要将类名大写以便您可以区分
classes, for example, from concrete objects or variables or functions.
类 例如 来自具体的对象、变量或函数
So if you go to our main.lua, on line 35,
所以如果你去我们的主卢瓦 在第35行
we're requiring a library, called class, which
我们需要一个名为类的库 它
is what's going to allow us to actually create these classes.
才能让我们真正创建这些类
Because classes are not native--
因为班级不是原生的--
they are in a sense a native Lua feature,
它们在某种意义上是原生的Lua功能
but Lua's way of doing object oriented programming is a little bit convoluted.
但是Lua进行面向对象编程的方式有点复杂
Some folks have kindly put together a library that makes it a lot simpler,
一些人好心地建立了一个库 使它变得简单得多
and a lot more closely related to other languages that do object oriented
与其他面向对象的语言有更密切的关系
programming more predominantly, like Java or C#, or even Python,
更主要的是编程 比如Java或C# 甚至是Python
allow us to use the keyword class in a way that's very similar to those
允许我们以非常类似的方式使用关键字CLASS
libraries.
图书馆
On line 39 and 43, we're acquiring our own code, paddle and ball,
在第39行和第43行 我们正在获取自己的代码、球拍和球
and we're going to take a look at those right now so we
我们现在就来看看这些 所以我们
can see what a class looks like.
可以看到班级是什么样子的
So I'm going to go ahead and open up a--
所以我要继续开一家--
the ball file, ball.lua.
球文件 bal.lua
And we can see here all we need to do just
我们可以在这里看到我们所需要做的就是
to create a ball class is, using our class library, ball gets class,
创建一个Ball类是 使用我们的类库 Ball获取类
and then curly brackets like that.
然后是像这样的花括号
And so now we have a class object, a class table,
所以现在我们有了一个类对象 一个类表
effectively, because everything in Lua is a table.
实际上 因为Lua的一切都是一张桌子
But we can think about it in terms of objects.
但我们可以从物体的角度来考虑它
We have a class object called ball, and then we
我们有一个名为Ball的类对象 然后我们
can start to define functions that belong to this class.
可以开始定义属于此类的函数
So we're going to define what's called a constructor, or an init function
因此 我们将定义所谓的构造函数或初始化函数
in this case, an initializer.
在本例中 为初始值设定项
And it's going to allow us to initialize our ball with whatever we want.
它将允许我们用任何我们想要的东西来初始化我们的球
In this case, we want to start our ball off with an x and a y
在本例中 我们希望以x和y开头
and a width and a height.
宽度和高度
And notice within here we have a word called self.
请注意 在这里我们有一个词叫“自我”
Self and this are common words in object oriented programming languages
Self和This是面向对象编程语言中的常用词
that mean whatever object we're creating with this class is going to be self.
这意味着我们用这个类创建的任何对象都将是self
So we'll see that--
所以我们会看到--
we'll see that shortly.
我们很快就会看到这一点
Self.x gets x.
Self.x得到x
So whatever concrete object we create using this call,
因此 无论我们使用此调用创建什么具体对象
this init call, set its x to this x, set its y to the y, set its width,
这个init调用 将它的x设置为x 将y设置为y 设置其宽度
set its height.
设置它的高度
That specific object.
那个特定的物体
Self.
赛尔夫
And then we're doing the same thing for delta y and delta x,
然后我们对增量y和增量x做同样的事情
only that we are setting those two random values just as we did before.
只是我们正在设置这两个随机值 就像我们以前做的那样
Self.dy, self.dx.
Self.dy self.dx
That belongs to whatever specific object gets instantiated using this init call
它属于使用此init调用实例化的任何特定对象
as we'll see in the code.
正如我们将在代码中看到的那样
We're defining just a reset function here just to make it easy.
为了简单起见 我们在这里只定义了一个重置函数
Before we had a--
在我们有一个--
several lines of code that set our ball to the middle of the screen
几行代码将我们的球设置到屏幕中央
and gave it a random velocity.
给了它一个随机的速度
We're doing that now, and this is a good way of sort
我们现在正在这样做 这是一种很好的排序方式
of refactoring out groups of logic.
重构出一组逻辑
We're creating a function called reset that just does that all in one function
我们正在创建一个名为Reset的函数 该函数在一个函数中完成所有这些操作
call, and we just call that within our main function, condensing our code.
调用 我们只是在Main函数中调用它 压缩我们的代码
And then notice we have an update and a render function now.
然后请注意 我们现在有一个更新和一个呈现函数
And we are going to call these from our own update
我们将从我们自己的更新中调用这些
and our own draw function such that every object
和我们自己的绘制函数 以便每个对象
that we want in our game, every entity, and we'll build upon this game
我们希望在我们的游戏中 每个实体 我们将在这个游戏的基础上
by game in the future.
在未来的比赛中
We'll just call update and render on everything from our main.lua,
我们将只调用更新并呈现来自我们的main的所有内容 lua
and defer all of that to each individual class and objects
并将所有这些都交给每个单独的类和对象
so we don't have to have a main.lua that's like 800 lines of code.
所以我们不需要有一个Main Lua 这就像是800行代码
We just break out all of the updates that are pertinent to the ball here,
我们只是在这里发布所有与球相关的更新
and all the render code that's pertinent to the ball here,
以及所有与球相关的渲染代码
call each individual balls update and render,
调用每个单独的球更新和渲染
and save ourselves a lot of time in refactoring.
节省了我们大量的重构时间
We're doing the same thing if we look at paddle.
如果我们看桨 我们也在做同样的事情
Paddle's a class, as well.
划桨也是一门课
It gets the reason the class library.
它得到了类库的原因.
Same exact sort of thing here, xy with height, and a dy.
同样的事情 xy加上高度 还有dy
In this case, we're just initialising that to zero so that we're not moving.
在这种情况下 我们只是将其初始化为零 这样我们就不会移动
And then we're calling the update function here.
然后我们在这里调用update函数
So if our dy is less than zero, we're using the math.max function as before,
所以如果dy小于零 我们就像以前一样使用math.max函数
with the top edge of the screen, and then whatever our y plus our current dy
与屏幕的顶部边缘 然后无论我们的y加上我们的当前dy
is, so delta y.
是Δ y
And then here, self.y gets math.min, virtual height
然后这里 self.y得到math.min 虚拟高度
minus self.height, self.y plus self.dy times delta time.
减去self.height self.y加上self.dy乘以delta time
So that's the clamping behavior that we saw before with the paddles, only now,
这就是我们之前看到的用桨的夹紧行为 只是现在
we took it from main and we put it in our update function
我们把它从main函数中取出来放到update函数中
so each paddle calls its update, and we take some lines
所以每个paddle调用它的更新
of code out of our main file.
我们的主文件中的代码
And then it has its own render function here, same as the paddle.
然后它有自己的渲染功能 和桨一样
The render function for the paddle and the render function for the ball
球拍的渲染函数和球的渲染函数
are effectively the same.
实际上是一样的
And so if we go to our main, we-- we're acquiring the paddle
所以如果我们去到我们的主管道 我们--我们得到了桨
and we're acquiring ball so that we can use them.
我们正在获取球 以便我们可以使用它们
So if we go down to line 79, instead of initializing our ball dx or ball dy,
所以如果我们向下到第79行 而不是初始化我们的球dx或球dy
ball x, ball y, paddle y, player 1y, player 2y,
球x 球y 桨y 玩家1 y 玩家2 y
now, we have player one is simply paddle 10, 35, 20.
现在 我们有一个参与人是简单的桨10 35 20.
And player two is a paddle, virtual width minus 10,
参与人2是球拍 虚拟宽度减10
virtual height minus 30, 520.
虚拟高度减30520
Ball is a ball, virtual width divided by two minus two,
球是一个球 虚宽除以二减二
virtual height minus two, minus two, [? five by ?] two
虚高减二减二五是？两
minus two, four and four.
负二四四
So those paddles now have control over their own x and y, their own width
所以这些桨现在可以控制自己的x和y 自己的宽度
and height, and the battle-- or the ball has its own control over the xy width
和高度 以及战斗--或者球对XY宽度有自己的控制
and height.
和身高
And the self applies to this object.
而自我也适用于这个对象
This is whatever self was in our constructor that we saw before.
这就是我们之前看到的构造函数中的self
So even now we can just call-- so we can simply
所以即使是现在我们也可以直接呼叫--所以我们可以简单地
say player 1.x player 1.width, player 1.y, and everything is contained.
假设玩家1.x 玩家1.wide 玩家1.y 一切都包含在内
We don't need a million variables to keep track
我们不需要一百万个变量来跟踪
of all the things going on in our game.
在我们比赛中发生的所有事情中
And this is going to be especially important as we scale, and we have--
随着规模的扩大 这一点将变得尤为重要 我们已经--
maybe we have 100 things on the screen at one time.
也许我们一次可以在屏幕上看到100个东西
We don't want 100 times x variables where
我们不希望100乘以x个变量
x is, however many properties that thing has that we need to keep track of.
X是 不管它有多少我们需要跟踪的属性
It's all the same logic except, now, we're
这都是同样的逻辑 除了 现在 我们
calling player one update and player two update in our update function,
在我们的更新函数中调用玩家一更新和玩家二更新
instead of having all that logic therein,
而不是让所有的逻辑都在里面
where they're moving and then keeping track of whether
他们在哪里移动 然后跟踪是否
or not they're going past the top and bottom edges of the screen.
否则 它们会越过屏幕的顶部和底部边缘
And then if game state is play, we're now just calling ball update.
然后 如果游戏状态是PLAY 我们现在只需要调用球更新
And these are all getting passed in delta time.
而这些都是在三角洲时间内通过的
And then same thing here.
然后这里也是一样的
Instead of having all that logic for restating the ball
而不是用所有的逻辑来重申球
as one block of code, we took it out, we refactored it,
作为一段代码 我们把它取出来 我们重构了它
we put it into our ball class, and now all we have to do
我们把它放到球课上 现在我们要做的就是
is just one line of code, ball or reset.
只是一行代码 球或重置
And then here down on line 169 in our draw function,
然后在我们的绘图函数的第169行
we just have player one render, player two render, ball render.
我们只有一号玩家渲染 二号玩家渲染 球渲染
And later on as we scale and we make games
后来 随着我们的规模扩大 我们制作游戏
that have a lot more things on the screen, a lot more entities,
屏幕上有更多的东西 更多的实体
we can just do these renders in a loop.
我们可以只在循环中进行这些渲染
We can just say for each entity in our screen, just render it.
我们只能说 对于屏幕中的每个实体 只需呈现它
For each entity in our screen, just update it.
对于我们屏幕中的每个实体 只需更新它
We can condense thousands-- hundreds of lines of code
我们可以压缩数千--数百行代码
into just a few lines of code by deferring update logic
通过推迟更新逻辑 只需几行代码
and rendering logic to each individual entity,
以及将逻辑呈现给每个单独的实体
thanks to object oriented programming.
多亏了面向对象的编程
And so that's how we're going to refactor using classes.
这就是我们将如何使用类进行重构
So any questions on how any of that works so far?
那么 到目前为止 对这一切是如何运作的有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
This is a good point, I think, to take a five minute break.
我认为这是一个很好的观点 可以休息五分钟
And once we come back, we'll talk about how to look at frames per second.
一旦我们回来 我们将讨论如何查看每秒的帧
All right.
好的
So we're going to take a minute just to look at something kind of small,
所以我们要花一分钟时间来看看一些小东西
but often it's the case where in games if we
但通常情况是 在游戏中 如果我们
want to make sure that we are performing like our applications performing well,
希望确保我们的性能与我们的应用程序一样运行良好
we want to-- some way to monitor our frames per second.
我们想要--某种方式来监控我们的每秒帧数
And so I figured I would just take a second
所以我想我应该花点时间
to illustrate this quickly so that we can use this in the future.
来快速地说明这一点 这样我们就可以在未来使用它
The two functions that are going to be important for us here--
对我们来说很重要的两个功能--
well, the first of these is just a little small cosmetic addition
好的 第一个只是一个小小的化妆品
to the application.
添加到应用程序
It's just love.window.setTitle.
这只是love.window.setTitle
Title, so far our application, I'm not entirely sure what the--
标题 到目前为止我们的申请 我不完全确定是什么--
it says by default, I think it says--
它默认地说 我想它说--
what does it say-- untitled.
上面写了什么--没有标题
Yeah.
嗯
So that's not-- it's a layer of lack of polish, more or less.
所以这不是--这是一层或多或少的缺乏光泽
And it'd be nice just to solve that problem quickly.
如果能迅速解决这个问题 那就太好了
So we're going to call a function called love.window.setTitle, some string,
所以我们将调用一个名为love.window.setTitle的函数
which will solve that problem quickly.
这将很快解决这个问题
We can make it look as if we have that detail down.
我们可以让它看起来像是我们已经把细节记下来了
And then the thing that's actually going to let us determine whether or not
然后 实际上将让我们决定是否
we are running well or we're running very poorly
我们要么跑得很好 要么跑得很差
is a function called love.timer.getframespersecond.getFPS,
是一个名为love.timer.getfraMesperSecd.getFPS的函数
which is something that LOVE graciously gives us for free
这是爱无偿赐予我们的东西
and allows us to very easily slap it wherever we want.
让我们可以很容易地随心所欲地拍打它
We can print it to the console, or we can just
我们可以将其打印到控制台 或者我们可以
draw it straight to our application.
直接将其绘制到我们的应用程序
In this case, we're going to do the latter.
在这种情况下 我们将执行后一种操作
So I'm going to go ahead and go into LOVE--
所以我要继续前进 去爱--
or Pong 6 in our main.
或者是我们主场的乒乓球6
If we go ahead and look at line--
如果我们继续看这条线--
where is it-- line 64.
它在哪里--64行
love.window.setTitlePong, just quick and easy.
Love.window.setTitlePong 简单快捷
Now, our window header is set appropriately,
现在 我们的窗口标题被适当地设置
and if we go down to line 198, here I've decided
如果我们下到198号线 我已经决定
to sort of split out this in a separate function,
为了在一个单独的函数中对其进行拆分
called display FPS on line 198.
在第198行调用了Display FPS
And the function is defined on line 207, so a function display FPS,
并且该函数是在行207上定义的 因此函数显示FPS
takes no parameters.
不使用任何参数
Its only goal is to just draw our current FPS to the screen.
它的唯一目标是将我们当前的FPS绘制到屏幕上
So we're going to set our current font to a small font.
所以我们要将当前字体设置为小字体
We're going to set our color-- so this is what I alluded to before in that we
我们将设定我们的颜色--这就是我之前提到的 我们
can set LOVE's rendering color to some RGBA quadruple,
可以将Love的渲染颜色设置为RGBA的四倍
and anything that we draw beyond that point will then be drawn at--
而我们画出的任何超出这一点的东西都会被画在--
it'll be drawn into whatever that color is.
不管是什么颜色 它都会被吸引过来
So, in this case, we're giving it red of zero, 255 on the green, zero blue, 255
所以 在这种情况下 我们给它红色 0,255 在绿色 0 蓝色 255
fully opaque, which has the effect of setting our color to just
完全不透明 其效果是将我们的颜色设置为
completely green.
完全是绿色的
And then love.graphics.print, our current FPS--
然后是love.raphics.print 我们目前的FPS--
string, and then our current FPS here, which is love.timer.getFPS.
字符串 然后是当前的FPS 即love.timer.getFPS
But it's going to return that as a number, and by default,
但它会将其作为一个数字返回 并且默认情况下
Lua does not allow you to concatenate strings and numbers,
Lua不允许您连接字符串和数字
so we're going to concatenate here with this ..operator,
所以我们要在这里连接这个运算符
which is the way of doing string concatenation in Lua.
这是在Lua中进行字符串连接的方法
We're going to call the two string function.
我们将调用两个字符串函数
So we're going to take in love.timer.FPS,
所以我们来看看Love Timer.FPS
we're going to make it a string, and then
我们要把它做成一根线 然后
we're going to concatenate it here.
我们将在这里将其连接起来
And then we're going to call love.graphics.print on that value,
然后我们将在该值上调用love.graph print
and then we're going to put it at 10, 10.
然后我们会把它设为10 10
So shift it just a little bit from the top left edge of the screen.
所以把它从屏幕的左上角移一点
So that's going to have the effect of the go to Pong 6, and we run it.
因此 这将产生Go to Pong 6的效果 我们运行它
We can see now it starts at zero and 52 because it
我们现在可以看到它从0和52开始 因为它
has to gather a few frames of data before it
必须在它之前收集几帧数据
has a number we can actually use.
有一个我们可以实际使用的数字
But we see there FPS at 60, and so our game runs, otherwise, just the same.
但是我们看到FPS在60 所以我们的游戏运行 否则 还是一样的
Completely random.
完全是随机的
A little bit broken, but that's OK, we'll fix it up.
有点坏了 不过没关系 我们会修好的
But currently we have a problem, and that's
但目前我们有一个问题 那就是
that our ball is just going straight through our paddles.
我们的球直接穿过了我们的球拍
So how can we fix this problem?
那么 我们如何解决这个问题呢？
We need some way of detecting collision.
我们需要一些检测碰撞的方法
So in 2D games, generally, there's a concept of aa bb collision detection.
因此 在2D游戏中 通常存在AA、BB碰撞检测的概念
And what this is is axis aligned bounding box collision detection, which
这是轴对齐边界框碰撞检测 它
means that we have bounding boxes, just rectangles, quads,
意味着我们有边界框 只有矩形、四边形、
which have an x and a y and a width and a height which are nonrotated.
它们具有不旋转的x和y以及宽度和高度
So they're completely aligned with our axes.
所以它们完全与我们的轴线对齐
They're completely parallel perpendicular.
它们是完全平行垂直的
So the only way that we can get this easy math, the aa bb collision
所以我们能得到这个简单数学的唯一方法 AA-BB碰撞
detection working is if we have no rotation of our boxes.
如果我们的盒子没有旋转 检测工作就会起作用
They have to be completely aligned.
它们必须完全一致
But if they are, we have a very simple algorithm,
但如果是这样 我们有一个非常简单的算法
which is we're just making sure that no edges of our boxes
那就是我们只是要确保我们的盒子没有边缘
are outside the opposite edges of our-- of the other rectangle.
在我们的--另一个矩形的相对边缘之外
So if we have one rectangle-- and I'll illustrate this on the screen here.
所以如果我们有一个矩形--我将在这里的屏幕上说明这一点
We have two rectangles.
我们有两个长方形
If this top edge is below this edge, we know
如果这条顶边在这条边下面 我们知道
no matter what, they're not going to inter-- they're not intersecting.
无论如何 它们不会相交--它们不会相交
There is no way it can because it's below here.
它不可能做到 因为它就在下面
So no matter where it is on the x and the y, if it's below here,
所以不管它在x轴和y轴上的什么位置 如果它在这里下面
it's not a collision.
这不是撞车
If this edge is on this side of this rectangle,
如果这条边在这个矩形的这一边
we know, as well, there's no way those two boxes can overlap.
我们也知道 这两个盒子不可能重叠
And it applies to every edge as long as it is the opposite edge.
它适用于每一条边 只要它是相对的边
So if this edge is below this one, if this edge is above this one,
所以如果这条边在这条下面 如果这条边在这条上面
if this edge is on the right, and this edge is on the left,
如果这条边在右边 这条边在左边
it means that no matter what, those boxes aren't colliding.
这意味着无论发生什么 这些盒子都不会碰撞
So we can simply do four conditions.
所以我们可以简单地做四个条件
We can say, if rec1.x is not greater than rec 2.x, plus rec2.width,
我们可以说 如果rec1.x不大于rec2.x 加上rec2.wide
and rec1.x plus rec1.width is not less than rec2.x,
并且rec1.x加上rec1.wide不小于rec2.x
so if the two edges are not beyond their opposite edges, same thing with the y,
所以如果这两条边没有超出它们的相对边 y也是一样的
and the y plus rec1.height, we know that we have a collision.
Y加上rec1的高度 我们知道我们有碰撞
We know that because we haven't fulfilled any of those criteria.
我们知道这一点 因为我们还没有达到这些标准中的任何一项
But we know that if that's not true, if the--
但我们知道 如果这不是真的 如果...
one of the edges is not beyond the opposite edge, then it's--
其中一条边没有超过另一条边 那么它--
we do have a collision.
我们确实发生了碰撞
So it is going to be true.
因此 这将是真的
So we'll see that here in our code.
因此 我们将在代码中看到这一点
The go to Pongs 7, at line 113, we have a function
Go to Pong 7 在第113行 我们有一个功能
that we're calling called ball collides.
我们称之为球碰撞
Our ball class has a function called collides.
我们的Ball类有一个名为Collides的函数
So let's go ahead and take a look at our ball class.
那么让我们继续来看看我们的球课
And in this case, we've defined our function such
在本例中 我们将函数定义为
that it takes in a paddle parameter, so it's
它接受一个划桨参数 所以它是
going to compare against another rectangle that
将与另一个矩形进行比较 该矩形
has an xy and a width and a height.
具有XY和宽度和高度
And we're saying that if rx is greater than the paddle x, plus the paddle
我们说 如果rx大于划桨x 再加上划桨
width, which means if rx is greater than the right edge.
宽度 这意味着如果RX大于右边缘
So if our top left is greater than the--
所以如果我们的左上角大于--
or just our left-- is greater than the right edge,
或者就是我们的左边--比右边大
we know that we can't collide.
我们知道我们不可能相撞
Same thing if it's greater than the other rectangles,
如果它比其他矩形大 情况也是一样的
self.x plus self.width.
Self.x加上self.wide
No, sorry.
不 对不起
In that case, if the paddle's x is--
在这种情况下 如果球拍的x是--
it basically the same operation but from the paddle's perspective.
它的操作基本相同 但从划桨的角度来看
If the paddle is greater than the rectangle on the right side,
如果球拍大于右侧的矩形
if it's farther along the right side past the right edge,
如果它沿着右侧更远地越过右侧边缘
we know that there can be no collision.
我们知道不可能发生碰撞
It's just impossible.
这是不可能的
Same thing with y.
Y也是如此
If the y-- self.y, so this ball is y--
如果y--self.y 那么这个球是y--
is greater than the paddle's y, plus the paddle height.
大于划桨的y 加上划桨高度
So if it's below the edge of the paddle, because we're
所以如果它在桨的边缘以下 因为我们是
taking the height into consideration, or if the paddle's y is greater
考虑到高度 或者如果划桨的y更大
than this ball's y plus self.height, then we
比这个球的y加本身高 然后我们
know that that also can't be a collision.
要知道 这也不可能是碰撞
But if that's not true, then we need to return true.
但如果这不是真的 那么我们需要返回真
And so if we go back to our main-- no, that's the wrong main.
所以如果我们回到主干道--不 那是错误的主干道
We go back to main.lua here.
我们回到Main 这里是Lua
We're calling ball.collides.
我们要把球打成碰撞球
So if we're in our game state, if we're in our-- sorry,
所以如果我们处于我们的游戏状态 如果我们处于--抱歉
if we're in our play state, if game state is equal to play,
如果我们处于游戏状态 如果游戏状态等于游戏
if the ball collides with player one, so player one is the left paddle.
如果球与一号球员相撞 那么一号球员就是左桨
So if there's a collision detected, the ball.dx and dx is our x velocity.
因此 如果检测到碰撞 那么球.dx和dx就是我们的x速度
So it's whatever direction it's moving on the x-axis.
所以它在x轴上移动的方向是什么
So it's going to be moving to the left if it's gone--
所以如果它消失了 它就会向左移动--
if we detected a collision.
如果我们检测到碰撞
And it doesn't matter whether it's moving left or right,
它是向左还是向右移动并不重要
but we needed-- what we need to do is set it to its negative value.
但我们需要--我们需要做的是将其设置为负值
Because if it's moving left and we said--
因为如果它向左移动 我们说--
let's say it's moving left at its negative 20 pixels and we set to 20,
假设它在负20像素处向左移动 我们设置为20
the dx is now 20, it's going to start moving to the right.
DX现在是20 它将开始向右移动
It's going to have the effect of inverting its x velocity
它会产生反转其x速度的效果
and, therefore, reversing its direction.
因此 扭转了它的方向
But what we're also doing here with times 1.03
但我们在这里用1.03倍做的
is we're multiplying a little bit just to speed up the game.
我们只是为了加快比赛速度而增加了一点
Because we don't want the game to into perpetuity just have the same velocity.
因为我们不希望游戏进入永恒 只是有相同的速度
It's not going to ramp up the excitement.
这不会增加人们的兴奋感
We want to keep things going, we want to get some momentum going,
我们想要让事情继续下去 我们想要获得一些动力
so what we're going to do is call ball.dx
所以我们要做的就是把Ball.dx
equals its negative value times a scaler that we've determined arbitrarily.
等于它的负值乘以我们任意确定的定标器
In this case, I've decided it should be point--
在这种情况下 我决定这应该是重点--
1.03 so it'll increase it by 3% every time.
1.03 所以每次都会增加3%
And then in the event that we have a--
然后如果我们有一个--
our ball-- because it's getting added, its x velocity is getting
我们的球--因为它被添加了 它的x速度
added each frame to its position, we want
将每个帧添加到其位置 我们希望
to make sure that it's not like inside of our paddle.
以确保它不会像在我们的桨里面一样
Because it is possible that it could shift a certain number of pixels
因为它可能会移动一定数量的像素
to the left, or to the right, because the same operation applies.
向左或向右 因为适用相同的操作
Such that the two are sort of like on top of each other.
因此 这两者有点像在彼此的顶部
We want to re-- we want to shift it, we want to reset it.
我们想要--我们想要改变它 我们想要重置它
So what we're going to do-- because it'll detect another collision
所以我们要做的是--因为它会检测到另一次碰撞
immediately if that's the case.
如果是这样的话马上就去
If it, on the next frame, it's within that paddle,
如果它 在下一帧中 它在那个球拍内
it's going to say that it's still colliding with that paddle
它会说它仍在与那把桨相撞
so it's going to shift its velocity again.
所以它会再次改变速度
And it's going to have the effect of it infinitely sort of bouncing
它将产生无限弹跳的效果
back and forth within the paddle.
在划桨内来回摆动
We don't want that to happen.
我们不希望这种情况发生
So if we detect a collision, we want to shift it.
因此 如果我们检测到碰撞 我们想要移动它
We want to make sure it's completely outside of the paddle's collision box.
我们想要确保它完全在拍子的碰撞框之外
So we're saying ball.x gets player one.x, plus five.
所以我们说的是 bal.x得到玩家1 x 加上5
Plus five because that's the width of the paddle.
加5 因为这是桨的宽度
So that has the effect of just once you detect a collision, negative set--
所以这只有一次你检测到碰撞的效果 负集--
x velocity to negative, and then instantly
X速度变为负值 然后立即
shift it right on the right edge of the left paddle.
把它向右移到左桨的右边
And we're doing the same thing here.
我们在这里也在做同样的事情
If ball collides a play or two, we're doing the-- we're negating or inverting
如果球撞上了一两个球 我们就是在做--我们在否定或颠倒
its x velocity.
它的x速度
And then-- this is the same exact operation,
然后--这是同样的手术
but since it's based on the-- the left top left corner,
但由于它是基于--左上角
we can't minus it by five, that wouldn't make sense.
我们不能减去5% 那就说不通了
We're going to minus it by four because that's the width of the ball.
我们要把它减去4 因为那是球的宽度
So if we minused it by five, we would have one pixel of space.
所以如果我们把它减去5 我们就会有一个像素的空间
We plussed it by five on this example, because we're
我们在这个例子中加了5 因为我们是
coming in from the right side.
从右边进来
We want to just make sure that it's right on the right edge of the paddle,
我们只想确保它在划桨的正确边缘
so we're setting it to player one.x.
所以我们将其设置为玩家1e.x
And in this case, we're using the minus four
在这种情况下 我们使用的是负四
because that's the width of the ball.
因为这就是球的宽度
So we want to shift it to the left, the width of the ball,
所以我们想把它移到左边 球的宽度
and that will have the effect of the right paddle, if there is a collision,
这将产生右桨的效果 如果发生碰撞
it'll just get shifted over, and the right-- the ball
它只会被移到另一边 右边--球
will be touching the paddle right on their two edges.
将在他们的两个边缘接触到球拍
Here on line 118, we're solving the problem we had before of what
在第118行 我们解决了之前的问题
happens when the--
发生在...
oh, sorry, that's actually not what I was thinking of.
哦 对不起 我想的不是这个
This is the-- if there's a collision, then we want the ball's y velocity
如果有碰撞 我们需要球的y速度
to randomize every time.
每次都是随机的
So this has the effect of when we're playing the game
所以当我们玩这个游戏的时候
and we've detected a collision between the two paddles,
我们检测到两个电极板发生了碰撞
we don't want the same angle back and forth every time
我们不想每次都从同一个角度来回
because then the game will just infinitely take place the exact same--
因为这个博弈会无限地重复
the same angle will just keep happening over and over again.
同样的角度会不断重复
We don't that to happen.
我们不希望这样
We want some variability in terms of how the ball bounces off the paddle.
我们希望球从球拍上反弹的方式有一些变化
So what this does is, still within the condition,
所以这个方法的作用是 仍然在这个条件下
if the ball collides with player one, we're
如果球与一号玩家相撞
going to, say, if the y velocity of the ball is negative,
如果球的y轴速度为负
then we want to keep it going negative.
那我们就想让它一直是负的
We still want the ball-- like if the ball's coming
我们还是想要球--就像如果球来了
at a sort of an upward angle and it bounces off the paddle,
以一种向上的角度 它从球拍上弹开
we want the x velocity to shift.
我们希望x速度移动
We want it to go to opposite direction, but we want the ball to keep going up.
我们希望它向相反的方向运动 但我们希望球继续向上运动
We don't want the ball to like bounce back down, which
我们不想让球反弹回来
wouldn't make any sense.
完全说不通
We don't want to negate the y velocity.
我们不想忽略y方向的速度
So we're going to keep the y velocity negative,
所以我们保持y速度为负
we're going to set it to a negative value between 10 and 150.
我们将它设置为10到150之间的负值
And it's just arbitrary.
这是武断的
You can set that to whatever you want.
你可以随意设置
And then we're going to do the same thing if the y velocity is positive.
如果y方向的速度为正 我们也要做同样的事情
We want the ball to--
我们想让球
we want the ball to go in the positive direction if it's already coming down.
如果球已经落下来了 我们希望它朝正方向运动
So we're doing the exact same thing here.
所以我们在做同样的事情
It's the same logic in the player two instance.
在参与人2的例子中也是一样的逻辑
And then this was what I thought I was looking at before for a second,
然后我以为我看到的是这个
but this is how we fix the issue of the upper and lower boundary of the screen.
但这就是我们如何解决屏幕的上下边界的问题
Right.
对的
Because it's one thing to solve the fact that we have the paddles
因为这是一件事来解决我们有桨的事实
now deflecting the ball, but we don't want the ball
现在让球偏转 但我们不想要球
to infinitely go above the top edge of the screen,
要无限地高于屏幕的顶部边缘
or the bottom edge of the screen.
或屏幕的底边
So this is just a simple if condition.
所以这只是一个简单的if条件
We're just saying if the ball's less than or equal to
我们只是说如果球小于或等于
zero, which means if the ball's at the top edge of the screen,
零 这意味着如果球在屏幕的顶端
just set it to zero, so make sure it doesn't
只需将其设置为零 确保它不会
go above the edge of the screen, and then negate its wide velocity,
走到屏幕边缘上方 然后否定它的宽速度
so it's instantly going to start going downwards.
因此 它会立即开始向下
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: This question is about Pong 7, line 113.
观众：这个问题是关于乒乓球7号第113行的
Couldn't the shifting of the balls dx and y
难道球dx和y的移动不能
be done in the ball collides function, if there is a collision?
在做球碰撞功能时 如果有碰撞？
COLTON OGDEN: The shifting of the ball's function if ball collide-- no,
科尔顿·奥格登：如果球相撞 球的功能会发生变化--不
collides the ball-- the collides function
撞球--碰撞功能
is a-- it just returns true or false.
是--它只返回真或假
So it would be--
所以它会是--
I mean, I think you probably could refactor it out that way,
我的意思是 我认为你可以用这种方式重构它
but the purpose of collides isn't to have
但碰撞的目的并不是为了
any sort of side effects like that.
任何像那样的副作用
Its only purpose is just to return true or false.
它的唯一目的只是返回True或False
Because we can do any-- we could have any sort of behavior we want.
因为我们可以做任何--我们可以有任何我们想要的行为
In a collides function, we may not necessarily want to shift the ball
在碰撞函数中 我们可能不一定想要移动球
or do anything, we might just want it return true
或者做任何事情 我们可能只希望它返回TRUE
and print something to the console.
把一些东西打印到控制台上
So, in terms of, I think, in an engineering perspective,
所以 我认为 从工程学的角度来看
it makes more sense just to have a simple true or false function,
只要有一个简单的真或假函数就更有意义了
and then determine how you want that to actually influence your game
然后确定你希望它如何真正影响你的比赛
state inside your main function, or inside some other function.
在您的主函数或某个其他函数中声明
OK.
好的
And so, Yeah, we went down here.
所以 是的 我们去了这里
The top edge of the screen, and then bottom edge of the screen.
屏幕的顶部边缘 然后是屏幕的底部边缘
If the ball.y, it's same exact thing, just the bottom edge of the screen.
如果是球 那也是一样的东西 只是屏幕的底部边缘
If the ball.y is greater than or equal to virtual height minus four,
如果球Y大于或等于虚拟高度减4
and we're doing virtual high minus four, why?
而我们做的实际上是四分之差 为什么？
AUDIENCE: Could get stuck at the bottom
观众：可能会卡在底部
COLTON OGDEN: Exactly.
科尔顿·奥格登：没错
So we want to make sure that we write-- as soon as we--
所以我们想确保我们写下--只要我们--
the bottom edge of the ball touches the bottom of the screen,
球的底边接触屏幕的底部
we want to detect a collision, then we want to say ball.y, the--
我们想要检测碰撞 然后我们想说球 Y 那个--
gets virtual height minus four in case it overshot the bottom edge
获取虚拟高度减去4 以防超出底部边缘
based on how much time has elapsed and how much the velocity is,
根据经过了多少时间和速度有多大
you want to instantly put it right up so that it's at the edge
你想立刻把它立起来 这样它就在边缘
so it's a clean bounce.
所以这是一次干净利落的反弹
And then we want to negate the y velocity just the same
然后 我们想要同样地否定y速度
as we did up above.
就像我们在上面做的那样
And so if we run our program here, Pong 7, looks the same,
因此 如果我们在这里运行我们的程序 Pong 7 看起来是一样的
but now the ball's bouncing.
但现在球开始反弹了
And note that it got a neg-- it got a random-- it
注意 它得到了一个否定的--它有一个随机的--它
looks like it's going below the bottom edge
看起来像是在底部边缘以下
because the monitor is currently at 720 and that's the window resolution,
因为显示器当前的分辨率是720 这是窗口分辨率
but it is bouncing off the bottom edge as well.
但它也在从底部边缘反弹
And the angle, if you'll note, is a little bit different every time,
如果你注意到 每次的角度都有一点不同
because we are giving it a random y velocity, a y--
因为我们给它一个随机的y速度 a y--
yeah.
嗯
And then that's influencing-- oh, I messed up.
然后这就是影响--哦 我搞砸了
I wanted to illustrate the speed increase.
我想要举例说明速度的提高
It's going to take a little bit of time.
这需要一点时间
But every time it detects a collision, it is going to be scaling its--
但每次它探测到碰撞 它就会扩大它的--
the x velocity by 1.03.
X速度增加了1.03倍
So it's going to make it a little bit faster.
所以它会让它更快一点
Now, currently, the y angle's a bit steep,
现在 Y角有点太陡了
so it's going to take forever to illustrate that.
所以这需要永远的时间来说明这一点
But we'll see that in a later example.
但我们将在后面的示例中看到这一点
So we have the basics of our game.
因此 我们已经掌握了游戏的基本知识
But how are we keeping score?
但我们如何计分呢？
What's the determining factor for how we keep score in Pong?
决定我们如何在乒乓球项目上得分的因素是什么？
Left or right.
左或右
As long as it goes past the left or right edge of the screen.
只要它穿过屏幕的左边缘或右边缘
So what do we need to thereby do?
那么 我们需要做些什么呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: We do need a counter, and we
科尔顿·奥格登：我们确实需要一个柜台 我们
need to also monitor whether the ball has
还需要监控球是否有
collided with the left or the right boundary of the screen.
与屏幕的左边界或右边界发生冲突
And then have that increment that counter.
然后让计数器递增
So we're going to go ahead and take a look at Pong 8
所以我们接下来来看看乒乓球8
to see how this is implemented.
看看这是如何实施的
We have here on line 88 and 89 some counter variables, player one score,
我们在第88行和第89行有一些反变量 一号玩家得分
player two score.
二号玩家得分
We've had those for a long time, but we haven't used them.
我们已经拥有它们很长时间了 但我们还没有用过它们
We've only used them to draw to the screen.
我们只是用它们来画到屏幕上
We're actually going to now increment them, and show them as scorekeeping
我们现在实际上要递增它们 并将它们显示为记分
variables in our code here.
我们代码中的变量
I thought I had implemented it in Pong 8,
我以为我已经在《乒乓球8》中实现了
but I think I might have left out the actual incrementing of the score.
但我想我可能遗漏了分数的实际增量
But this is the logic that's pertinent to that example.
但这就是与这个例子相关的逻辑
So if ball.x is less than zero, which just
因此 如果bal.x小于零 这只是
means if we've gone past the left edge of the screen,
意味着如果我们已经越过了屏幕的左边缘
ignore serving player for now.
暂时忽略发球手
The important thing is now we are doing player two score,
重要的是 我们现在是在为二号选手得分
gets player twp score, plus one.
获得玩家TWP分数 加1
Just a simple increment.
只是一个简单的增量
And then we're resetting the ball.
然后我们重新设置球
Same thing for here.
这里也是一样
If the ball.x is greater than virtual width,
如果Ball.x大于虚拟宽度
so pass the right edge of the screen, and actually it could be ver--
所以通过屏幕的右边缘 实际上它可能是--
if ball x plus four is greater than virtual width,
如果球x加4大于虚拟宽度
then and it will have the same effect.
那么 它也会产生同样的效果
But, actually, no, because we want to make sure
但是 事实上 不是的 因为我们想确保
that we don't see the ball at all when they score.
当他们得分时 我们根本看不到球
So, yeah, this is actually correct.
所以 是的 这实际上是正确的
If ball.x is greater than virtual width, then serving player gets two,
如果Ball.x大于虚拟宽度 则发球手得到2
player one score is player one score plus one.
一人得分等于一人一分加一
And then we're going to reset the ball.
然后我们要重置球
Serving player.
发球手
So now what we need to talk about is the idea of serving.
所以现在我们要谈的是服务的理念
So when we start up the game--
所以当我们开始游戏的时候--
so let's go ahead and take a look at--
那么让我们继续来看看--
we're going to go to Pong now so we're going to go straight to Pong 9,
我们现在要去Pong 所以我们要直接去Pong 9
and then we need to take a look at what a state machine is.
然后我们需要看看什么是状态机
So currently in the game, we've talked about state a little bit.
因此 目前在游戏中 我们已经讨论了一点状态
We've had the start state, which means the game is ready for us
我们已经进入了开始状态 这意味着比赛已经准备好了
to just press Enter and then the ball will go off in a random direction.
只需按下Enter键 球就会以随机的方向飞出
And then we have the play state.
然后我们得到了播放状态
And the play state is set to our paddles interacting with the ball,
比赛状态被设置为我们的球拍与球相互作用
and then keeping track of score, basically.
然后基本上记录下分数
A state machine is very important.
状态机非常重要
It's a ubiquitous concept in game development.
这在游戏开发中是一个普遍存在的概念
It just means, how can we monitor what state we're in
这只是意味着 我们如何监控我们所处的状态
and what transitions take place between those states to bring out new states.
以及这些状态之间发生了什么转变 以产生新的状态
And each individual state has its own logic.
每个单独的州都有自己的逻辑
And by breaking out the logic of these states separately,
通过将这些状态的逻辑分开
we can scale our code much bigger and not have monolithic code for--
我们可以将我们的代码扩展得更大 而不是针对--
this particular diagram is an example of what you might have as a state
这张特殊的图表是一个例子 说明了你可能会有什么状态
machine for a character like Mario where you have a ducking state, a release
机器对于像马里奥这样的角色来说 你有一个躲避状态 一个释放
state which takes the down-- the in-- like the input of down.
接受向下的状态--向内--就像向下的输入
So if we're releasing down, it'll become standing.
所以如果我们往下放 它就会变得站立
So ducking state, the transition is release the down key,
所以在俯冲状态下 转换为松开向下键
he becomes standing.
他站了起来
Standing key, press the down key.
站立键 按下向下键
He becomes ducking, these are states and transitions.
他开始躲避 这些都是状态和转变
These individual states are the overall representation of his behavior
这些单独的状态是他行为的总体表现
at large, basically.
基本上 总体上是这样的
And the same logic applies to our game.
同样的逻辑也适用于我们的游戏
We have a play state, we have a serve state.
我们有比赛状态 我们有发球状态
We want to have maybe a game over state.
我们想要在州立大学打一场比赛
If someone scores 10 points, then it should say, oh, the winner is x.
如果某人得了10分 那么它应该说 哦 获胜者是x
And you can define any arbitrary number of states, it--
你可以定义任意数量的状态 它--
which depends upon your model, whatever game you want to develop.
这取决于你的模型 无论你想要开发什么游戏
For example, like Super Mario has a title screen,
例如 就像超级马里奥有一个标题屏幕一样
maybe your game has like a high score state.
也许你的比赛已经达到了高分状态
You want to display all the high scores in your game
您想要显示游戏中的所有高分
and we'll actually show that in a lecture next week.
我们将在下周的一堂课上展示这一点
But this is what a state machine is.
但这就是状态机的含义
It's just a-- it can be in any one particular state at one time,
它只是--它可以同时处于任何一种特定的状态
and the transitions are what allow you to go in between your states.
而这些转变让你可以在你的状态之间切换
And each state does have transitions in and out of other states.
而且每个状态都有进出其他状态的转换
And we're going to use this in Pong 9.
我们将在Pong 9中使用这一点
So beyond illustrating the score, we're going
所以除了说明比分之外 我们还将
to start keeping track of more than just the start and the play state.
开始跟踪的不仅仅是开始和播放状态
We're actually going to start modeling the serve state.
我们实际上要开始对发球状态进行建模
And so let me go ahead and illustrate what this looks like.
所以让我继续说明这是什么样子的
So if we're here, I just pressed Enter.
因此 如果我们在这里 我只需按Enter键
We started at the start state as normal, but I pressed Enter
我们像往常一样从开始状态开始 但我按了Enter
and now it says player one serve.
现在它写着一号玩家发球
So we're actually serving.
所以我们实际上是在提供服务
And so if I press Enter again as it instructs me,
因此 如果我按照它的指示再次按Enter键
player one is on the left, the ball should move to the right.
一号球员在左边 球应该移到右边
Which it does.
事实的确如此
So I'm going to go ahead and lose on purpose as player two.
因此 作为二号玩家 我将继续努力 故意输掉比赛
And now it's player two's serve.
现在轮到二号选手发球了
So whichever character, whichever player loses should get to serve again.
因此 无论哪个角色 无论哪个球员输了 都应该再次发球
And so now if I press Enter, note when we
现在如果我按Enter键 请注意当我们
were player one, the ball moved to the right.
如果是一号球员 球就会向右移动
So for player two, the ball moves to the left.
因此 对于第二名球员来说 球向左移动
So we have now a little bit more interaction.
因此 我们现在有了更多的互动
We have different states.
我们有不同的州
We start off the game, and then we serve, and we play.
我们开始比赛 然后发球 我们打球
So when the ball's live, when we're actually doing this,
所以当舞会直播的时候 当我们真的在做这个的时候
we're in the play state.
我们现在处于游戏状态
Now we're in the serve state.
现在我们处于服务状态
So what's the transition between the--
那么在这两个--
sort of the play state and the serve state?
某种打球状态和发球状态？
What's the transition there?
那里的过渡是什么？
We score a point.
我们得了一分
So if we are looking at our state diagram and we're in the play state,
因此 如果我们查看我们的状态图 并且我们处于播放状态
the transition to the serve state is x player scores a point.
转换到发球状态是x玩家得了一分
And then if we're in the serve state, the transition
然后 如果我们处于服务状态 转换
is someone presses enter.
有人按了Enter键
Enter key gets pressed.
按下Enter键
And so that's how we want to think about our games
这就是我们想要如何看待我们的游戏
if we have a bunch of different sets of, sort of logic,
如果我们有一系列不同的逻辑
that we can sort of take out of our game and think about conceptually,
我们可以从我们的游戏中拿出来 从概念上思考
it allows us to break our game up into a bunch of different modes and states,
它允许我们将游戏分解成一系列不同的模式和状态
and not really get overburdened by all these variables
而不是真的被所有这些变数负担过重
that maybe need to keep track of-- or what state are we in?
可能需要跟踪--或者我们处于什么状态？
Like what are all these variables doing?
比如 所有这些变量都在做什么？
And we'll see how we can break this out in a more
我们将看看如何在更多的时间里解决这个问题
modular fashion in future weeks.
未来几周的模块化时尚
Note that right now, currently all we're doing is
请注意 现在 目前我们所做的是
we're setting a state variable to some string here,
我们在这里将状态变量设置为某个字符串
and just doing if conditions on it, which
只要有条件就可以了
works fantastically for small examples.
对于小的例子来说 效果非常好
So if, like, for example, if we're in the update function and game state--
所以 如果 比如说 如果我们处于更新功能和游戏状态--
see, over here we're saying if the game state is set to serve,
看 在这里我们说的是 如果游戏状态设置为服务
then we're initializing all of the variables.
然后我们对所有变量进行初始化
And if the game state is play, then we need
如果游戏状态是PLAY 那么我们需要
to actually perform our logic here.
在这里实际执行我们的逻辑
So if the-- if we're in play, this is going to get called,
所以如果--如果我们在玩这个游戏 这将被称为
each frame, and we're going to say, if ball collides with player one,
每一帧 我们要说 如果球与一号球员相撞
do all this stuff.
做所有这些事情
And then this allows us to sort of think of our game.
然后 这让我们可以在某种程度上考虑我们的游戏
It's almost like having separate update functions within our update function.
这几乎就像在我们的更新函数中拥有单独的更新函数
And we'll actually see how we can take these out of one update
我们将实际了解如何从一次更新中删除这些内容
function in future weeks with a actual state machine class
在未来几周使用实际的状态机类
and implement things a little bit more abstractly.
把事情实现得更抽象一点
But suffice to say, now, whenever we want to like, for example,
但我要说的是 现在 无论何时我们想要 例如
make a transition, if someone scores here,
做一个过渡 如果有人在这里得分
like if we're going to the left side of the screen,
例如 如果我们要转到屏幕的左侧
it's ball x is less than zero.
它的球x小于零
All we have to do is just set this state to serve
我们所要做的就是将这个状态设置为
and our update function is then going to update appropriately.
然后 我们的更新功能将进行适当的更新
So any questions on how sort of state machines or the state
所以有什么关于状态机或国家的问题吗
works here in the context of Pong?
在乒乓球的背景下工作？
Yes.
是
AUDIENCE: So the state machine is the relationship to the state
听众：所以状态机就是与国家的关系
or is the container of the states?
抑或是国家的容器？
COLTON OGDEN: The state machine is sort of a--
科尔顿·奥格登：国家机器是一种--
the overall conceptual look at what your different states
总体概念性地查看您的不同状态
are and their transitions, yes.
是和他们的转变 是的
And in future weeks we're not implementing a state machine
在接下来的几周里 我们不会实施状态机
object or a class here.
对象或类
But in future weeks, we will see the state machine class
但在接下来的几周里 我们将看到状态机类
that manages transitions between different states in a more
管理不同状态之间的转换
modular and clean fashion.
模块化和干净的时尚
All we're doing here is our state machine
我们在这里所做的就是我们的状态机
is just if statements and saying if the state is equal to this, then do this.
就是if语句 如果状态等于this 那么就这样做
And then change the state to some value.
然后将状态更改为某个值
AUDIENCE: So the state machine is a concept?
观众：所以状态机是一个概念？
COLTON OGDEN: It is a concept.
科尔顿·奥格登：这是一个概念
Yeah.
是啊
But we will see an implementation of a state machine as an object next week.
但是下周我们将看到状态机作为一个对象的实现
Any more questions?
还有问题吗
OK.
好的.
Cool.
酷了
So currently we have scoring.
目前 我们有得分
As we saw, the player one score and player two score are getting
正如我们看到的 参与人1和参与人2的得分
incremented now and, therefore, getting rendered to the screen
现在递增 因此呈现在屏幕上
whenever we go to the left or the right edge.
无论我们走到左边还是右边
So we're keeping track of score.
所以我们在记录分数
But what do we need now in order for someone to win?
但是我们现在需要什么才能让某人赢呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
观众：[听不见]
COLTON OGDEN: Sorry?
科尔顿·奥格登：什么？
COLTON OGDEN: Yes it does.
科尔顿·奥格登：是的
Exactly.
没错
So it's actually quite simple.
所以其实很简单
All we need to really do is just an if statement, right?
我们真正需要做的就是一个if语句 对吗？
If someone's score is equal to some value, 10, then some player has won.
如果某个人的得分等于某个值 10 那么某个玩家赢了
So if we look at player-- if you look at Pong 10, we go to main,
如果我们看参与人 如果你看乒乓球10 我们去主区
and go to here, line 174, and also line 160,
然后转到这里 第174行 还有第160行
we can see that all it literally is is in our logic
我们可以看到它的字面意思是在我们的逻辑中
from before, where we're just testing to see whether the ball is
之前我们只是测试球是否
gone beyond the left or the right edge.
超出了左边或右边的边缘
Because this is effectively where you need to do your check anyway
因为这是你需要做检查的地方
to see whether someone scored a point.
看看是否有人得分
So all we're doing is adding logic to that part of the program
所以我们所做的就是在程序的这一部分增加逻辑
and saying after we increment their score.
在我们增加他们的分数后说
If it's equal to 10 we're setting a value called the winning player.
如果它等于10 我们就设置一个值 叫做获胜玩家.
We're going to set it to two.
我们把它设为2
So if the ball.x is less than zero, then that means that player one got
如果ball.x小于0 那就意味着参与人1
scored on because it went pass the left edge of the screen.
因为球越过了屏幕的左边
Therefore, player two score should go up.
因此 参与人2的得分应该上升
And, therefore, the winning player should be, too, if the player two or--
因此获胜的参与人也应该是 如果参与人2或者
two score is equal to 10.
2分等于10分
And in this case, see, we're here, we're setting a new state done,
在这种情况下 看 我们在这里 我们正在设置一个新的州完成
and then if that's not the case, or if their score is still less than 10,
如果不是这样 或者如果他们的分数仍然低于10分
we should still-- we should set it back to serve, and then reset the ball.
我们还是应该--我们应该把球放回发球位 然后重新设置球
And so if we go to our update function, here--
所以如果我们转到我们的更新功能 这里--
actually, we're doing it in our update phase.
实际上 我们正在进行更新阶段的工作
So, currently, if it's the done state, the ball gets reset
因此 目前 如果它是完成状态 则球被重置
but no update is being applied to the ball in that case.
但在这种情况下 没有对球进行更新
We still have scores 10.
我们还有10分
It'll still render the score, so score whoever's got 10
它仍然会呈现分数 所以谁得到10分就得分
and it'll show the other player's score.
它会显示另一位选手的分数
And the actual logic that applies here, whenever
无论何时何地 实际的逻辑都适用于这里
we want to break out of that state, is in our love.keypressed key function.
我们想要摆脱那种状态 就是在我们的爱情里 按键功能
We see you're on line 227.
我们看到你在227线上
If game state is equal to done, which we set it to before,
如果游戏状态等于完成(我们之前将其设置为)
and this will only execute if they've pressed
只有当他们按下
Enter or return, so it's effectively waiting
进入或返回 所以它实际上是在等待
for them to press Enter or Return.
让他们按Enter或Return
You want to set game save back to serve.
您想要将游戏保存设置回发球
We want to reset the ball.
我们想要重置球
We want to initialize those scores back to zero.
我们希望将这些分数初始化为零
So we're setting up a brand new game, effectively.
因此 我们正在有效地建立一个全新的游戏
If the winning player is one, then we'll give serving player to two
如果获胜的玩家是一名 那么我们就把发球手分配给两名
so that they have the advantage on the next game,
这样他们就能在下一场比赛中占据优势
and then otherwise set it to one.
然后将其设置为1
And if we go down to our render function, so down to line 275,
如果我们向下转到呈现函数 那么向下转到第275行
if we're in the done state, then we should render to the screen player
如果我们处于完成状态 那么我们应该渲染到屏幕播放器
and then winning player, because, remember,
然后是获胜的球员 因为 记住
we set winning player to one or two, depending on whether--
我们把获胜的玩家设为1或2 这取决于--
depending on who won and who scored the tenth point.
这取决于谁赢了 谁得了第十分
We'll say player one or two wins, and we'll just render that and then
我们会说一个或两个玩家赢了 然后我们会呈现出来 然后
press Enter to restart after that.
之后按Enter键重新启动
And that's the logic for that.
这就是这一点的逻辑
And we can see this in playoffs.
我们可以在季后赛中看到这一点
If it's too slow, we might not have to go through an entire run.
如果速度太慢 我们可能不需要跑完全程
But I sped up the--
但我加快了.
whoops-- I want to actually get the ball back.
哎呀--我真的想把球拿回来
I set up the speed so it's-- we're in the serve state,
我设置了速度 所以我们处于发球状态
we're in the play state, it's up-- the ball bounced back.
我们处于比赛状态 球反弹回来了
It's going to be a bit tedious, but suffice to say, it's a big payoff.
这将是一个有点乏味 但足以说 这是一个很大的回报
Don't worry.
别担心
Should have set the speed a little faster.
应该把速度调快一点
Almost there.
快到了
It's getting tense.
气氛越来越紧张了
And player one wins.
一号玩家赢了
So there we-- we're also setting the font to a larger size, and in the code
所以我们--我们也把字体设置成更大的尺寸 在代码中
I create a new font object that's basically
我创建了一个新的字体对象
between the small font and the score font, which is a large font.
在小字体和大字体之间
So 16 size font.
所以是16号字体
And so player one wins, and that's really all it boils down to.
所以一号玩家赢了 这就是最终结果
Just keeping track of your counter and just making sure that when you do
我只是在跟踪你的计数器 确保当你这样做
hit 10 in your logic for detecting the screen collisions,
在你的逻辑中点击10来检测屏幕冲突
that you set the state to done.
你设置的状态
And if the state is done, then you just need to monitor keyboard input
如果状态为done 则只需要监视键盘输入
and see whenever someone presses enter.
看什么时候有人按回车键
Someone press Enter in our love.keypressed,
有人在我们的爱中按下回车键
it does the-- it has the effect of setting
它的作用是
player-- it's player two serve because player one won so that's only fair.
是二号选手发球因为一号选手赢了 这样才公平.
We're going to press Enter to serve and then we begin a brand new game.
我们要按回车键发球然后我们开始一个全新的游戏
And that's simple.
这很简单
So now we have an infinitely playable game with a bunch of simple states.
所以现在我们有了一个无限可玩的博弈 有一堆简单的状态
We're missing a very important detail, though, in my opinion,
我们忽略了一个非常重要的细节 在我看来
and that's sound.
这就是声音
Currently, our game is just very--
目前我们的游戏非常--
it's great, the gameplay all works.
这是伟大的 游戏的所有作品.
Everything is working fine, but just missing a little polish.
一切都很好 只是缺少一点抛光
And so what we're going to do is we're going
所以我们要做的就是
to start adding audio to the game, which is, in my opinion,
开始在游戏中加入音频 在我看来
one of the more fun things to add because it also means you're
其中一个更有趣的事情是
close to the end of your project.
接近你的项目结束
Love.audio.newsource is a function we're going to look at here.
Love.audio.newsource是一个我们要在这里看的函数
All this is going to do is take a path and then optionally a type.
所有这一切都要做的是采取一个路径 然后可选的类型
And this path is going to be to a sound file,
这个路径是指向一个声音文件的
and it's going to create an audio object that you can play back
它将创建一个音频对象 你可以回放
at any point in your application.
在您的应用程序中的任何位置
So what we're going to effectively do is just whenever a collision happens,
所以我们要有效地做的就是每当碰撞发生时
depending on what type of collision it is, we'll just play a particular sound.
根据碰撞的类型 我们只播放特定的声音
And a program that I really like to use for all of this,
还有一个我真的很喜欢用来做这一切的程序
and I-- what I encourage you guys to download
我--我鼓励你们下载
if you want to start tinkering with your own sounds for your project,
如果你想开始为你的项目修改你自己的声音
is a program called bfxr.
是一个名为bfxr的程序
It's free on Windows and Mac.
它在Windows和Mac上是免费的
I'm not sure if they have a Linux port.
我不确定他们是否有Linux接口
They might have a Linux port of a similar program called sfxr
他们可能有一个类似程序的Linux移植 名为sfxr
which is what this is based off of.
这就是这件事的基础
But what this allows you to do is just generate a bunch of random sounds.
但这样做只会产生一串随机的声音
And I can illustrate that shortly for you.
我很快就可以为你们说明这一点
If you would like to grab it, it's on bfxr.net.
如果你想获取它 它在bfxr.net上
It's a super quick download and--
这是一个超级快速的下载 而且--
here, I'll actually-- I'll demonstrate it just so we can see how it plays out.
在这里 我将实际--我将演示它 这样我们就可以看到它是如何进行的
So this is the interface.
这就是界面
Make sure I have some audio.
确保我有一些音频
And then there is a lot of different presets here.
然后这里有很多不同的预置
So there's pickup slash coin, laser slash shoot.
因此 有拾取斜线硬币 激光斜线射击
It's meant for sort of like small games like this,
它是为像这样的小游戏而设计的
like implementing on the fly prototype audio type stuff.
比如在运行中实现原型音频类型的东西
But you can see, it just implements--
但你可以看到 它只是实现了--
I'll turn that down, it's a little loud.
我把音量调小一点 有点吵
It-- we have power-ups, for example.
它--例如 我们有加电装置
So every time I click on this, it's going to give us a random power-up so.
所以每次我点击它 它都会给我们带来随机的启动
[COMPUTER SOUND EFFECTS]
[电脑音效]
And then randomized, you get all sorts of weird nasty stuff.
然后随机化 你会得到各种各样奇怪的讨厌的东西
And then-- the stuff that we'll use is blip slash select.
然后--我们将使用的内容是blip斜杠选择
Most of the things in our in like interfaces and games like Pong you
我们In中的大多数东西都像界面和Pong You这样的游戏
just want simple sounds like this.
只是想要这样简单的声音
So I've already done the work of generating a few sounds
所以我已经完成了产生几个声音的工作
that I thought fit pretty well.
我觉得很合适
I'll go ahead and show you the code first in Pong 11.
接下来我会先给你看《乒乓球11》的代码
If we go to-- if you'll see-- if you look at the directory structure,
如果我们去--如果你会看到--如果你看一下目录结构
you'll see we have a sounds folder.
您会看到我们有一个声音文件夹
In the sounds folder, I've created three sounds, paddle hit, which
在声音文件夹中 我创建了三种声音 Ppale Hit
is anytime the paddle hits the ball.
是球拍击球的任何时候
Score, which is when any-- anytime the ball
得分 这是当任何时候--任何时候球
goes past the left or the right boundary of the screen.
越过屏幕的左边界或右边界
And then wall hit, so any time the ball touches
然后撞墙 所以任何时候球触地
the top or the bottom of the screen.
屏幕的顶部或底部
And so the logic of this is extremely simple.
因此 这其中的逻辑非常简单
All we need to do is whenever--
我们所需要做的就是--
we already have it implemented, so all we need to do is--
我们已经实施了 所以我们需要做的就是--
oh, first thing, I should say, and this is a good illustration of a table.
哦 首先 我要说的是 这是一张桌子的很好的插图
And we'll start to see this a lot more in the future.
在未来 我们将开始更多地看到这种情况
We didn't really use tables much in this lecture,
我们在这堂课中并没有太多地使用桌子
but the table is Lua's like sort of be all, end all, data structure.
但表是Lua的一种BE ALL END ALL的数据结构
It's the dictionary-- Python dictionary, JavaScript object.
它是字典--Python字典 JavaScript对象
It's an array, it's everything that you need for anything
它是一个数组 它是您所需的一切
beyond simple variables in Lua.
超越Lua中的简单变量
It's what everything, even like classes in other libraries are made out of.
它是一切事物的基础 甚至像其他库中的类一样
In this case, we're just initializing a table here called sounds,
在本例中 我们只是在初始化一个名为Sound的表
and we're passing in three keys so it takes-- it can take in key value pairs,
我们传递了三个键 所以它可以--它可以接受键值对
or you can just give it a list of values and it will create indices for them
或者 您只需给它一个值列表 它就会为这些值创建索引
implicitly.
含蓄地
Here, we're just passing in like you would do in Python or JavaScript.
在这里 我们只是像您在Python或JavaScript中所做的那样传入
Paddle hit, and note that it does need these square brackets in order
Par Hit 请注意 它确实需要按顺序排列这些方括号
to initialize key value pairs in a table like-- in this format here.
来初始化表中的键值对--格式如下
Paddle hit gets love.audio.newsource.
Paddle Hit得到了Love
And in this case, it just takes in a path,
在这种情况下 它只需要一条路径
so sounds slash paddle head dot wave.
于是响起了斜桨头点波的声音
And we're giving it the key word-- or the string static,
我们给它的关键字--或字符串静态
which is the type of asset it is--
这就是它的资产类型--
it's stored as.
它被存储为
So you can have either static or stream audio assets.
因此 您既可以拥有静态音频资产 也可以拥有流音频资产
So if they're static, they're loaded in memory
因此 如果它们是静态的 它们会加载到内存中
and they're kept in memory for the execution of your program.
它们被保存在内存中 用于执行您的程序
If they're stream, then they're loaded on the fly as needed
如果它们是流的 那么它们会根据需要在飞行中加载
by your game engine.
被你的游戏引擎
And streamed audio assets can be helpful if you
和流媒体音频资源 如果您
have a huge game with a ton of sounds and a long like large audio files.
有一个巨大的游戏 有大量的声音和像大型音频文件一样的长时间
You don't want to keep all those in memory, necessarily,
你不一定想要把所有这些都保存在记忆中
because that could take up many, many, many megs or gigs of audio.
因为这可能会占用很多、很多、很多兆或演出的音频
And if you're sort of loading assets on the fly,
如果你是在运行中加载资产
if you have dynamic loading in your game,
如果你的游戏中有动态加载
then that's another thing you should take into consideration.
那么这也是你应该考虑的另一件事
In this case, these are very tiny sound files,
在这种情况下 这些是非常小的声音文件
because they're like-- like a fraction of a second long.
因为它们就像--就像几分之一秒长
So we're just setting them all to static so they get preserved in memory,
所以我们只是将它们都设置为静态 这样它们就可以保存在内存中
and we're just loading all three of them into this table.
我们只是把他们三个都加载到这张桌子上
And if we want to refer to these later on, all we need to do is sounds--
如果我们稍后想要提到这些 我们所需要做的就是听起来--
we can either reference sounds.paddlehit, like that,
我们可以参考声音 PaddleHit 像这样
if we wanted to.
如果我们想的话
Because by default, Lua just gives you a dot keyword, sort of the way JavaScript
因为默认情况下 Lua只给您一个点关键字 类似于JavaScript
does its objects, with the same name as the key that you passed in,
它的对象是否与您传入的键同名
or you can do it the Pythonic way, which is, without the dot, sorry--
或者你可以用毕德式的方式来做 那就是 没有圆点 对不起--
with just square brackets and now have the same of-- those two are equivalent.
只有方括号 现在有相同的- 这两个是等价的
It won't work, though, if you decided to put a space in your key,
不过 如果你决定在钥匙上留个空格 那就没用了
it will, I believe, it will--
它会的 我相信 它会--
just won't work at all, but it may inject an underscore.
根本不会起作用 但它可能会注入下划线
I'll have to test it out and find out.
我得先测试一下 然后找出答案
But, generally, it's not best practice to use dot
但是 通常情况下 使用点并不是最佳实践
when you already have the keys lined up like this, anyway.
不管怎么说 你已经把钥匙排成一排了
And what you can do with strings that you
以及您可以使用您所使用的字符串
can't do with dot using the dot notation,
不能使用点号表示法处理点号
is dynamically generate a lookup of your table with you--
就是与您一起动态生成表的查找--
which you can do with strings, which you-- yeah,
你可以用弦来做这件事 你--是的
because you can't in a four loop do four something in table,
因为在四循环中你不能在桌子上做四件事
and then table dot something, that just won't work.
然后桌子上点了点东西 那是行不通的
But you can do for everything in your table
但你可以为你桌子上的每一件事做
and then look up the key as that value, that iterated value in your table.
然后在您的表中查找键作为该值 该迭代值
We'll see examples of that in future lectures.
我们将在以后的课程中看到这方面的例子
But that's just something to keep in mind.
但这只是一件需要牢记的事情
So we have our table here, a sounds table.
所以我们在这里有一张桌子 一张声音桌子
Oh, and-- and we have our sounds ready, they're loaded in memory.
哦 还有--我们的声音已经准备好了 它们加载在内存中
All we need to do now is wherever we have
我们现在要做的就是
anything that, like any collision in our code, we just do this.
任何事情 比如我们代码中的任何冲突 我们都会这样做
It's as simple as the table.
就像桌子一样简单
At the key that we want, colon, which is Lua's
在我们想要的键上 冒号 这是Lua的
way of calling a function of a class or a table.
调用类或表的函数的方式
Colon play, and the play function is part of the new source audio
冒号播放 播放功能是新源音频的一部分
object in LOVE that we created in the table,
我们在桌子上创造的恋爱中的对象
and that will just have the effect of just playing it once.
而这只会产生只播放一次的效果
You can set it to looping.
您可以将其设置为循环
You can say the sounds paddle hit, set looping to true,
您可以说出划桨的声音 将循环设置为真
and it will just infinitely play over and over again,
它会无限地一遍又一遍地播放
which we wouldn't want for a sound like this.
我们可不想听到这样的声音
It would sound obnoxious.
这听起来会令人讨厌
But if you have a music track, for example,
但如果你有一首音乐曲目 例如
in a level, or something like that, you would
在某种程度上 或者类似的东西 你会
want set looping to be true so that when it finally ends,
希望设置循环为真 这样当它最终结束时
your user isn't just playing a game in silence.
你的用户不仅仅是在默默地玩游戏
So we're doing it with paddle hit, we're doing it with wall hit as well.
所以我们用拍子击打 我们也用击墙
So I've named them appropriately so that it's easy to infer where
所以我给它们起了适当的名字 这样就很容易推断出它们的位置
and for what purpose the sound files are used.
以及声音文件被用于什么目的
So whenever they're at the upper or lower boundaries, play the wall
所以 当他们在上界或下界时 就玩围墙
hit sound, and then whenever the ball reaches
击打声音 然后每当球到达时
the left or the right edge of the screen,
屏幕的左边缘或右边缘
just play the score sound effect.
只要播放乐谱音效就行了
And so if we play our game, and this is always one of my more favorite parts
所以如果我们玩我们的游戏 这一直是我最喜欢的部分之一
is playing the game with audio because it just makes
正在用音频玩游戏 因为它只会让
such a difference, in my opinion.
在我看来 这是一个很大的差异
We get sound effects.
我们可以得到音效
It's a little thing, and it's very easy, but it adds-- it adds so much flavor.
这是一件小事 而且很容易 但它增加了--它增加了很多味道
And then (explosion), and there we go.
然后(爆炸) 我们就开始了
And then our game is practically implemented at this point.
然后我们的游戏实际上在这一点上实现了
There's just one more example that I would
再举一个例子 我会
like to show you guys, a small example, because all of the examples
我想给大家看一个小例子 因为所有的例子
thus far have had the resize equal-- resizable equals false.
到目前为止 RESIZE等于--SIZIZE等于FALSE
Sort of key in the push setup screen initializer,
在推送设置屏幕初始化器中输入某种键
and in case you want to have a game where you can resize your window,
如果你想玩一个可以调整窗口大小的游戏
all we need to do is call a function called love.resize,
我们所需要做的就是调用一个名为love.resize的函数
which takes a width and a height.
它需要一个宽度和一个高度
And what we're going to end up doing with that,
而我们最终要做的是
specifically, for our use case, because we're using push,
具体地说 对于我们的用例 因为我们使用推送
we're going to go to Pong 12.
我们要去乒乓球12号
And then if we go to main.lua we see here on line 85,
如果我们进入主星 我们在85号线上看到
I've changed resizable to equal true now so that it will actually
我现在已将可调整大小更改为等于True 因此它实际上
allow us to resize the application.
允许我们调整应用程序的大小
If that's false, you won't even be able to click and drag
如果为假 则您甚至无法单击和拖动
the bottom corner of the screen, it just won't let you do it.
屏幕的下角 它就是不让你这么做
And then all you have to do is call love.resizewidthheight,
然后你所要做的就是调用Love 大小宽度高度
and then pass in push resize with height.
然后传入随高度调整大小的Push
Because push underneath the hood takes a texture and renders to it,
因为引擎盖下面的推力会获得纹理并渲染到它上
and then upscaled it to fill your window,
然后把它放大以填满你的窗口
and so it needs to know what your current window dimensions are so
所以它需要知道你当前的窗口尺寸是多少
that it can upscale it to fit the right dimensions.
它可以将其升级到合适的尺寸
And push also adds things like letterboxing,
Push还增加了信箱之类的东西
which is convenient if you want to maintain the exact same aspect ratio.
如果您想要保持完全相同的纵横比 这是很方便的
And in a game where maybe you have the UI that's
在游戏中 你可能会有这样的用户界面
driven by the size of your application, this function
受应用程序大小的驱动 此函数
will be important because then you can resize your--
将是重要的 因为这样你就可以调整你的--
you can resize and reposition your UI elements appropriately.
您可以适当地调整UI元素的大小和位置
Because if your game is small, maybe you want certain parts of UI
因为如果你的游戏很小 也许你想要用户界面的某些部分
to be invisible, or in a different location
隐形 或在不同的地方
altogether, just so that you don't take up a ton of screen space,
总而言之 这样你就不会占用大量的屏幕空间
and just to accommodate all possible users of your application.
并且只是为了适应您的应用程序的所有可能用户
But that has the effect now of-- if we go into Pong 12
但现在的影响是--如果我们进入乒乓球12
and then run it, actually, might not even be able to use the but-- yeah,
然后运行它 实际上 可能甚至不能使用但是--是的
I can just do this now.
我现在就可以这么做了
I can resize it, and it'll maintain the virtual width and height
我可以调整它的大小 它将保持虚拟的宽度和高度
that we set it to before, because that's like first and foremost
我们之前设置的 因为这就像是最重要的
what push will do and it'll letterbox no matter
无论推什么 它都会投递信箱
what size your application is to make sure that it maintains that aspect
您的应用程序的大小是什么 以确保它保持这一方面
ratio.
比率
So if you're beyond that aspect ratio vertically or horizontally,
所以 如果你在垂直或水平方向上都超过了这个纵横比
you'll get the appropriate letterboxing for it.
你会得到适当的信箱
So it's super convenient.
所以这非常方便
You don't have to worry about your users getting super distorted aspect ratios,
你不必担心你的用户会得到超级扭曲的长宽比
because they are using some sort of unforeseen resolution.
因为他们使用了某种不可预见的解决方案
That will always maintain it even if it's super tiny
它将永远保持它 即使它是超级微小的
because their monitor is super thin.
因为他们的显示器超薄
It will always maintain the aspect ratio.
它将始终保持纵横比
But that's pretty much it for Pong, actually.
但实际上 对于Pong来说 这差不多就是这些了
We have a complete game, start to finish, and if you have any questions,
我们有一场完整的比赛 从头到尾 如果你有任何问题
I'd be happy to answer them.
我很乐意回答这些问题
Any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Cool.
凉爽的
All right.
好的
Well, I'm excited to teach the rest of this course to you guys.
好吧 我很高兴能把这门课的其余部分教给你们
We've only scratched the surface.
我们只是触及了皮毛
We have a lot more to cover.
我们还有更多的内容要讲
Next week, we'll actually be covering Flappy Bird
下周 我们将真正报道Flappy Bird
so we'll get some nice colorful graphics, which
所以我们会得到一些漂亮的彩色图形
is a stark difference to our black and white aesthetics today.
对我们今天的黑白美学来说是截然不同的
But that's it for Pong.
但对于Pong来说 就是这样
So thanks for coming.
所以感谢你们的光临